许多公司都声称自己是史上增长最快的公司
A lot of companies claim to be the fastest growing companies of all time.
但 Anthropic 其实真的是 你们在 2025 年初的年度经常性收入（ARR）就已经达到 10 亿美元
Anthropic actually is. You guys were at a billion ARR at the start of 2025.
我最后看到的数字是年度经常性收入达到 190 亿美元
The last number I've seen is 19 billion ARR.
也就是说在 14 个月里从 10 亿涨到 190 亿美元
That's one to 19 billion dollars in 14 months.
从历史上看 我们一直都是最小的那一个
Historically, we were very much the smallest,
也是这个领域里融资最少的参与者之一
least well-funded player in this space.
我们既没有像 Meta 或 Google 那样的自由现金流 也没有那样的分发能力
We didn't have the free cash flow or the distribution of a meta or Google.
我们也没有像 OpenAI 那样的先发优势
We didn't have the first mover advantage of an open AI.
我们能走到今天这一步 完全是个奇迹
It's a complete miracle that we've gotten to the stage that we have.
跟我们稍微讲讲 在 Anthropic 负责增长是一种什么样的体验
Give us just a glimpse of what it's like to be leading growth inside of Anthropic.
这是我这辈子做过最难的工作
It's the hardest job I've had in my life.
当你加入 Anthropic 的时候
You come into Anthropic,
你得明白 你过去大概有 50
you need to understand that 50,
60 甚至 70% 的做事方式都得直接扔掉
60, 70% of how you operate in the past just throw it out the door.
你们做过最聪明的增长举措之一 就是把从 ChatGPT 导入记忆这个点子做出来
One of the cleverest growth moves you all made was this idea of importing memory from ChatGPT.
在 AI 领域 激活是一个非常大的挑战
Activation is a really big challenge in AI.
我们开始思考如何把增长自动化
We are starting to look at how do we automate growth.
我们的增长平台团队在推进一个名为 CASH 的项目
Our growth platform team is driving this effort called CASH,
全称是 Claude 加速可持续超高速增长
which is Claude Accelerates Sustainable Hypergrowth.
我们怎样利用 Claude 来自动化增长实验
How can we use Claude to automate growth experimentation?
而且已经开始见效
And it's delivering results.
你们基本上是在未来生活
You're basically living in the future.
我们总在谈论指数级
We always talk about the exponential.
两年后我们能交付的产品价值 很可能会是今天的 1000 倍左右
The product value that we will deliver in two years time is probably like 1000x what it is today.
最好笑的是 我发现公司内部 线性图已经不酷了
The funniest thing is I've noticed internally Linear charts are just not cool.
一切都得是对数线性的
Everything is log Linear.
他们只会给我看对数线性刻度的图
It's just showing me a log Linear scale.
Today my guest is Amol Avasare.
今天我的嘉宾是 Amol Avasare
Amol is head of growth at Anthropic,
Amol 是 Anthropic 的增长负责人
而 Anthropic 正在经历史上前所未有的增长
which is on the most unprecedented growth run in history.
在过去的 14 个月里
In the past 14 months,
他们的年度经常性收入从 10 亿增长到超过 190 亿
they grew from 1 billion to over 19 billion in annual recurring revenue.
仅在过去几个月里 他们的收入就翻了一番
Just in the past few months, their revenue doubled.
他们一直在实现每年 10 倍的增长
They've been growing 10x year over year.
在这个体量上 这是前所未闻的
This is unheard of at this scale.
等到这一期节目播出的时候
By the time this episode comes out,
他们的收入会更高
their revenue will be even higher.
为了让大家对这个规模有点概念
To put this scale in perspective,
companies like Atlassian and Palantir and Snowflake,
像 Atlassian Palantir 和 Snowflake 这样的公司
已经存在了 15 到 20 年
which have been around for 15-20 years,
各自的年度经常性收入大概在 45 到 60 亿美元之间
each do something like 4.5-6 billion in ARR.
而 Anthropic 每隔几个月就能新增这么多年度经常性收入
Anthropic is adding this much ARR every few months.
如果光是这些还不够吸引你
And if that isn't interesting enough to you,
Amol, who leads growth at Anthropic,
那么在 Anthropic 负责增长的 Amol
本人也是一个非常了不起的人
is an incredible human.
He previously led growth at Mercury and Masterclass.
他之前在 Mercury 和 MasterClass 负责增长
在那之前 他既当过创业者 也做过投行从业者
Before that he was a founder and an investment banker.
更有意思的是 有件事大多数人都不知道
And most interestingly, something that most people don't know about him,
那就是 Amol 曾经遭受过严重的脑损伤
is that Amol suffered a severe brain injury.
他花了 9 个月时间重新学习如何走路 如何工作 以及如何不一直感到恶心
He had to spend 9 months relearning how to walk and work and just not be nauseous all the time.
几年前 他在我的电子通讯里写了一篇客座文章 分享了这个故事
He shared this story in a guest post in my newsletter a number of years ago.
我们在这次对话中也确实聊到了这件事
We actually chatted about this during the conversation.
这正是我最喜欢的那种对话
These are my favorite kind of conversations,
因为 Amol 和他的团队基本上是在未来生活
because Amol and his team are living in the future.
而他这次来 就是要告诉我们未来的走向以及会发生哪些变化
And he's come to tell us where things are heading and what's going to change.
在这一期节目里 Amol 前所未有地向我们展示了一家像 Anthropic 这样的公司是如何运作和增长的
And in this episode, Amol shares an unprecedented look at how a company like Anthropic operates and grows.
包括他们如何思考增长
Including how they think about growth,
他们把工作中的哪些部分实现了自动化
what parts of the job they've automated,
产品和增长岗位的未来
the future of the product and growth roles,
以及 Amol 最初是如何通过给 Mike Krieger 发冷邮件拿到这份工作的
how Amol got the job in the first place by cold emailing Mike Krieger,
以及更多内容
and so much more.
Amol 非常出色 你可以试着数数在这次对话中他让人震惊了多少次
Amol is wonderful and just try to count the number of times that he blew my mind during this conversation.
在我们正式开始之前
Before we get into it,
别忘了去 LennysProductPass.com 看看 那里有一大堆非常划算的优惠
don't forget to check out LennysProductPass.com for an incredible set of deals available
只对 Lenny 的通讯订阅者开放
exclusively to Lennies Newsletter subscribers.
话不多说 下面请出 Amol Avasare
With that, I bring you Amol Avasare.
Amol 非常感谢你来上节目 欢迎来到这个播客
Amol, thank you so much for being here and welcome to the podcast.
很高兴能来
Pleasure to be here.
Anthropic 的增长负责人 小菜一碟
Head of growth at Anthropic, no big deal.
很多来自各家公司的人上过这个播客 他们都声称自己所在的是增长最快的公司
I've had a lot of people come on this podcast from companies that claim to be the fastest
在历史上都是增长最快的公司
growing companies of all time.
And Anthropic actually is,
而 Anthropic 其实真的是
如果你看看它的增长轨迹的话
if you look at the trajectory,
我这儿有一些数字
I just have some of the numbers here,
让大家感受一下这有多夸张
just so people understand how absurd this is.
你们在 2025 年初的年度经常性收入是 10 亿美元
So you guys were at a billion ARR at the start of 2025,
到 2025 年年中涨到大概 40 亿
then hit something like 4 billion mid-2025,
到 2025 年底则达到 90 亿美元的年度经常性收入
then 9 billion ARR at the end of 2025.
而我最后看到的数字是 你们已经达到 190 亿美元的年度经常性收入
And the last number I've seen is you guys are at 19 billion ARR,
为了再给这个数字加一点背景
which, just to put a couple pieces of context here,
其中一点就是 你们在 14 个月里从 10 亿涨到 190 亿美元
one is that's from 1 to 19 billion dollars in 14 months.
我有太多问题想问
I have so many questions.
首先 你是怎么拿到这份工作的故事就非常有意思
First of all, the story of how you actually landed this role is really interesting.
先讲讲你是怎么得到这份工作的
Talk about how you got this role.
是的 稍微有点不走寻常路
Yeah, it's a little unorthodox.
很有意思的是 当我做入职培训的时候
So it's funny, when I did my onboarding,
他们会讲这一批入职员工（cohort）里 有多少比例是通过内推来的
they walked through what percentage of the cohort came through referrals,
有多少比例是通过在官网投简历来的
what percentage came through applying on the website,
又有多少比例是通过主动挖掘来的
what percentage came through sourcing.
而我完全不在这些类别里
And I was on none of those.
我当时就想 好吧 这还挺有意思
And I was like, okay, this is interesting.
基本上 我之所以来到 Anthropic 是因为我本来就是 Claude 的用户
And basically, the way that I got to Anthropic was that I was actually a user of Claude.
而且我用得非常频繁
And I was using it a lot.
我当时心想 哇 这帮人
I was like, man, these guys,
产品很棒 公司也很棒
great product, great company.
但他们显然还没有增长团队
But they really obviously don't have a growth team.
所以我就直接给 Mike Krieger 发了一封冷邮件
And what I did was I just sent Mike Krieger a cold email.
当时他是首席产品官
He was the chief product officer.
我给他发了一封冷邮件 大概意思是
I sent him a cold email saying like,
嘿 我很喜欢你们在做的事情 也很喜欢这个产品
hey, love what you guys do, love the product.
我觉得你们非常需要一个增长团队
I think you guys badly need a growth team.
想聊聊 而且我没想到他会回复
Want to chat. And I didn't expect he would respond.
然后他回复说
And he responds and says,
嘿 是的 我感兴趣
hey, yeah, I'm interested.
我们聊聊吧 这事还挺有意思的
Let's talk. And it's funny.
我当时并不知道 我的意思是 我根本不可能知道
I didn't know. I mean, I wouldn't have known.
他们当时并没有在招聘增长团队
They were not hiring for a growth team.
根本没有任何增长产品经理的岗位挂出来
There were no growth PM roles listed.
但就在那个时候 他们刚刚开始考虑要不要招一个增长团队
But they were just at that time starting to think about hiring a growth team.
所以时机非常好
So it was very good timing.
总之 就这样和 Mike 聊上了 然后顺理成章地往下发展
But yeah, one spoke to Mike and one thing led to another.
他说 我是他唯一一个通过冷邮件招进来的产品经理
He said, I'm the only PM that he's hired from cold email.
我觉得自己非常幸运 他当时决定回复了我的邮件
And I feel very lucky that he decided to respond to my email.
我之前完全不知道这个故事
I did not know this story.
这又是一个离谱的事实
That is another absurd fact.
很明显 你非常擅长冷邮件
Clearly, you're good at cold email.
你在这封冷邮件里做了什么 才抓住了他的注意力
What did you do in this cold email to get his attention?
我可以说 这些年我基本把冷邮件这件事打磨到极致了
I would say like I've basically perfected cold email over the years.
所以在我做创业者的时候
So when I was a founder,
我必须在这方面变得非常非常厉害
I had to get really, really good at this.
所以我发了大量冷邮件 不断打磨邮件主题
So I sent a lot of cold emails out and just honed the subject line,
以及正文内容和语气
the message and the tone.
所以基本上 在邮件主题里
And so basically, I have in the subject line,
首先从转化的角度来看
the first thing is like from a conversion standpoint,
别人看到这封邮件
someone sees the email,
必须愿意点开它
they need to click on it.
所以我有一套经过测试的文案 效果非常
And so I have a copy that I've tested that is like very,
打开率非常高
very high open rate.
所以…… 等等 这套文案到底是什么
And so... Wait, what is this copy?
还是说这是个秘密
Or is this a secret?
这是个秘密 好 那我们就先保密
It's a secret. Okay, we'll keep it.
这是一点 先让他们愿意打开邮件
So that's one, getting them to open.
第二点我觉得是一些策略 比如
I think the second is then the tactics of...
你得搞清楚
You need to understand like,
别人通常是在哪里被人联系的
where are people getting outreach?
如果所有人都在同一个渠道被人联系
And if everyone's getting outreach in one area,
而你也在那个渠道去找他们
and then you reach out to them there,
那你的回复率就不会太高
then you're not going to get as high of a response rate.
比如你可以想到 LinkedIn
So you can think about like LinkedIn,
也可以想到工作邮箱
you can think about like work email,
这些都是所有人都在用来发邮件的地方
these are things that everyone is emailing.
所以其实有办法拿到别人个人邮箱
So there's ways to get people's personal emails out there.
这就是我做的一件事
And so that's one thing that I did.
所以 好 我拿到了他的个人邮箱
And so, okay, I've got this personal email,
我也知道哪套文案好用
I know the copy that works.
接下来就是把邮件写得非常简短
And then it's just keeping it very short.
说明我是谁 为什么我很合适
And here's who I am, here's why I'd be a good fit,
然后说我们应该聊一聊
and we should chat.
而且这些事情通常是行不通的
And these things typically don't work.
所以你一定要多跟进几次
And then you should always follow up a few times.
我的经验法则是
I think my rule of thumb is like,
如果我真的很在乎这件事
if I really care about it,
我就应该一直持续联系对方 直到他们明确跟我说 请别再发了
I should just keep reaching out to them until they tell me like, please stop.
所以我本来会一直这么做下去
And so I would have, I would have kept doing that.
但他在最合适的时间就回复了
But he responded the best time.
一个优秀的增长人才擅长冷邮件和吸引别人注意力 这就说得通了
It makes sense that a talented growth person would be very good at cold email and getting people's attention.
所以这几乎就像一个面试环节
So that's almost like an interview step is just,
就是看我到底想不想读完这封邮件
did I want to read this email?
本期节目由本季首席赞助商 WorkOS 特别呈现
This episode is brought to you by our season's presenting sponsor, WorkOS.
What do OpenAI, Anthropic, Cursor, Vercel, Repl.it, Sierra, Clay, and hundreds of other winning companies all have in common?
OpenAI、Anthropic、Cursor、Vercel、Repl.it、Sierra、Clay 以及其他数百家成功公司都有一个什么共同点
他们都由 WorkOS 提供支持
They are all powered by WorkOS.
如果你在为企业级客户打造产品
If you're building a product for the enterprise,
你一定感受过集成单点登录
you've felt the pain of integrating single sign-on,
SCIM、RBAC、审计日志以及大型公司所需的其他功能
SCIM, RBAC, audit logs, and other features required by large companies.
WorkOS 把这些阻碍成交的难题变成可直接接入的 API 并提供一个现代化的开发者平台
WorkOS turns those deal blockers into drop-in APIs with a modern developer platform built
专门为 B2B SaaS 打造
specifically for B2B SaaS.
几乎所有我投资的 初步开始向企业级市场扩张的创业公司 最终都会选择和 WorkOS 合作
Literally every startup that I'm an investor in that starts to expand up market ends up working with WorkOS.
因为他们就是这方面最强的
And that's because they are the best.
不管你是想拿下第一个企业客户的种子期创业公司 还是在全球扩张的独角兽
Whether you are a seed-stage startup trying to land your first enterprise customer or a unicorn expanding globally,
WorkOS 都是让你满足企业级需求并释放增长的最快路径
WorkOS is the fastest path to becoming enterprise-ready and unblocking growth.
它本质上就是企业级功能领域的 Stripe
It's essentially Stripe for enterprise features.
访问 WorkOS.com 开始使用 或者直接加入他们的 Slack 那里有真正的
Visit WorkOS.com to get started or just hit up their Slack where they have actual
工程师随时为你解答问题
engineers waiting to answer your questions.
WorkOS allows you to build faster with delightful APIs,
WorkOS 通过好用的 API
完整的文档和顺畅的开发体验 让你构建产品更快
comprehensive docs, and a smooth developer experience.
现在就访问 WorkOS.com 让你的应用满足企业级需求
Go to WorkOS.com to make your app enterprise-ready today.
那么 跟我们简单讲讲 现在在 Anthropic 负责增长是一种什么样的体验
Okay, so give us just like a glimpse of what it's like to be leading growth inside of Anthropic right now.
这是迄今为止 增长速度遥遥领先的公司
The most, by far, fastest growing company in history.
这到底是什么感觉
Just what is it like?
我会说 这非常是一项全公司范围的努力
Yeah, I'd say it's very much a company-wide effort, right?
是的 我们是增长团队
So like, yes, we are the growth team.
我们做得不错
We have done great.
我觉得我们带来了很大的影响
I think we've driven a lot of impact.
但说实话 我们不能为公司的成功居功太多
But honestly, man, we can't claim too much credit for the success of the We,
因为 Anthropic 归根结底首先是一家模型公司和智能公司
as Anthropic, are really a model company and an intelligence company first and foremost.
真正推动我们成功的绝大部分功劳在于我们的研究团队
And so the lion's share of what has driven our success is our research team.
我认为我们拥有全世界最好的研究团队
We have, I think, the best research team in the world.
我们在推理和算力方面也有非常优秀的团队
We have great teams on inference and compute.
还有很多其他团队 比如 Claude Code
And then there's many other teams like Claude Code,
销售与市场（Go-to-Market）等等 我觉得他们比我们更值得称赞
Go-To-Market, etc., who I think deserve much more credit than us.
如果把视角拉远一点看
I think just zooming out,
回到你刚才提到的一些点
going to some of what you said earlier,
我们的增长轨迹简直疯狂
that the growth trajectory has just been insane.
那种收入每年 10 倍的增长趋势 从一开始就存在
That 10x year-on-year revenue growth trend has been there since the beginning.
我记得 2023 年是从 0 到 1 亿
I think 2023 was 0 to 100 mil.
2024 was 100 to 1.
2024 年是从 1 亿到 10 亿
去年则是从 10 亿到大概 100 亿
Last year was 1 to roughly 10.
回想我在 2024 年加入的时候
And I look back to when I joined in 2024,
收入达到了数亿美元规模
revenue was in the hundreds of millions.
而且按照这样的增长轨迹一路延伸到 2024 年底和 2025 年
And just that trajectory to the end of 2024 and 2025,
我入职的第二周
week two of when I joined,
我们就开始做 2025 年的收入规划
we're going into 2025 revenue planning.
我们做了基础情景和激进情景两套预测
And we have these base case and aggressive case scenarios.
然后 Dario 一直在推动采用激进情景
And Dario's pushing the aggressive case scenario.
大家都快被吓坏了
And people are freaking out being like,
心想我们到底要怎么才能做到这个目标
how the hell are we going to hit that?
而 Dario 的态度是，我觉得我们其实还能远远超过这个数字
And Dario's like, I think we can actually go much higher than that.
而我当时的反应是
And I'm coming in like,
这地方也太疯狂了
this place is crazy.
根本不可能做到
Like, there's absolutely no way.
结果后来真的做到了
And that happened, right?
然后你再看 2025 年底
And then you get to the end of 2025.
你会想，好吧，大数定律要起作用了
And it's like, okay, law of large numbers.
以 100 亿这个基数来看，这里肯定会明显放缓
There's going to be a pretty big slowdown here based on your baseline rate of 10 billion.
你们怎么可能继续保持这样的增长速度
How are you going to keep growing at this rate?
结果就是完全没有放缓
It just has not slowed down.
而且这些数字都是公开的
And those numbers are public.
你刚才提到的 190 亿这个数字是截至 2 月底的
The 19 billion number you quoted is from the end of Feb.
所以这个数字其实也已经过时了
So that is also out of date.
说真的，这简直太疯狂了
And look, it's absolutely insane.
最好笑的是，我在公司内部发现线性图现在一点都不酷
The funniest thing is something that I've noticed internally is Linear charts are just not cool.
没人关心线性图
No one cares about Linear charts.
所有东西都要用对数线性来看
Everything is log Linear.
必须给我看对数线性刻度的图
I have to show me a log Linear scale.
我们就是按这种刻度来思考问题的
And that's the scale we think.
总体来说，我们真的是在硬撑着往前冲
And I think overall, we're just really hanging on by the seat of our pants.
一边努力控制好增长
We're trying to manage the growth.
一边尽可能为用户做到最好
And do the best that we can for our users.
我之前在 Anthropic 跟一个人聊到你
I was talking to somebody at Anthropic about you.
他说基本上每当他们想让某个东西实现增长
And they said that basically anytime they want something to grow,
就会找你来帮忙
they ask you to help.
而且每次都很奏效 你刚才也提到
And it works. So you talked about just like,
现在的一切都很神奇、很惊人
things are magical and amazing.
比如 Claude 和你们做的所有工具本身就非常厉害
And like Claude and all the tools y'all built are amazing innately.
这也是它们能增长得这么快的一个重要原因
And that's a big part of the reason they grow.
我觉得很多在听的人会想
I think many people listening to this will be like,
有一个几乎什么都能帮你做的“微型神明”在那儿 你还能做什么
what do you even do with like a magical micro god that just can do anything for you?
那我们为什么还需要一个做增长的人
Why do we need a growth person?
你到底在做什么
What do you even do?
说说你主要都在关注哪些事情
Talk about just the stuff that you focus on.
还有你们团队做过的、真正加速了增长的几个典型成果
And maybe like a couple of the wins that your team has shipped that has helped accelerate growth.
我会说 他们也不算完全说错
I would say like they're not fully wrong, right?
我们非常非常幸运 拥有全世界最好的模型
Like we're very, very lucky to have the best models in the world.
也很幸运有像 Claude Code 和 Cowork 这样的产品
We're very lucky to have products like Claude Code and Cowork.
这些确实让我们的工作轻松了很多
It certainly makes life a lot easier.
但话说回来 我得说这是我这辈子做过最难的工作
Having said that, I would say this is like the hardest job I've had in my life.
而且你知道，作为一个曾经的创始人
And that's, you know, having been a founder,
也当过投行从业者 还做过其他类似的工作
having been an investment banker and other things like that.
这份工作真的很难 如果说我们在这里作为增长团队到底在做什么
It's tough. And if I look at what do we do as a growth team here,
归根结底 其实还是和普通公司会做的那些大类事情差不多
I think ultimately it's the same categories of things that you would think about at a normal company.
比如我们关心获客
So we care about acquisition,
怎么让更多人走进“门店”
how are we getting more people in the door,
以及这些进门用户的使用意图
the intent of the people coming through the door.
我们关心激活
We care about activation,
包括注册流程 把用户引导到合适的产品上 让他们真正用得起来
the signup flow, funneling people to the right products, making them successful.
我们也关心变现相关的事情
You know, we care about things like monetization,
比如从免费到付费的转化 定价和产品打包方式
free or paid conversion, pricing and packaging,
这些全都在我们的范围内
all of that stuff.
工作的类别其实是一样的
The categories of work is the same.
我觉得真正的区别大概在于
I think then probably the big difference is,
我大概有 70% 的时间都花在我们内部称之为
I would say that like roughly 70% of what I spend my time on is what we internally refer
“成功灾难”的事情上
to as success disasters.
就是某件事太成功了 以至于带动其他一堆东西开始出问题
And that is where like things have gone so well that other things are breaking now.
任何在高速增长公司待过的人
And I think anyone who's worked at companies that have gone through rapid growth,
you think like Facebook or Uber or DoorDash early on,
比如早期的 Facebook、Uber、DoorDash
都会非常有体感 这种规模化会带来一大堆挑战
they understand this viscerally where scaling this much just brings a lot of challenges.
所以你看获客这一类
So if you think about each of those categories on acquisition,
激活这一类 变现这一类
on activation, on monetization,
都充满了救火式的工作
there's just a ton of firefighting,
不停在各种紧急问题之间来回切换
jumping from one urgent thing to another.
而且往往非常痛苦
And it's often extremely painful.
有意思的是 你看所有的图表
And it's funny because you look at all the charts.
全都是绿色
All the charts are green,
一路向上一路向右
fully up and to the right.
但大家的感受却是
And everyone's just like,
情绪上依然会觉得很难熬
it can be quite tough emotionally still.
所以你得时不时跳出来意识到 能有这些问题其实已经很幸运了
And so you need to sort of step back and just realize that we're very lucky to have these problems.
但这就意味着我 70% 的时间
But that says 70% of my time,
基本都在为这些“成功灾难”救火
I'd say, is just these like firefighting of success disasters.
剩下 30% 才是比较标准的那种“基本盘”增长工作
And I think the 30% remaining is just much more standard bread and butter growth work,
会更偏主动一些
where it's like more proactive.
比如你会去想
So you think about, okay,
在资源有限的情况下
if we have limited resources,
都有哪些产品 我们有很多不同的产品
which are the products? We have many different products.
哪些产品值得我们重点加码
Which of the products do we want to put some juice behind?
我们长期的定价和打包策略应该是什么样
What is our long-term pricing and packaging look like?
尤其是在技术快速变化 用户行为和参与模式不断迁移的背景下
Especially given that the technology is changing a lot and behavior and engagement trends are shifting.
还有就是我们会不断有新产品上线
And then things like we have a lot of new products coming up.
比如说 Cowork 上线了
Like, okay, you ship Cowork.
接下来呢 作为增长团队 我们应该在什么时间点介入
Now what? When is the right time that we should lean in as a growth team to start optimizing the
开始优化 Cowork 的核心采用漏斗
core adoption funnel for Cowork?
所以大概就是 70% 疯狂救火
So it's probably 70% just crazy firefighting,
30% 做这些基本盘工作
30% more bread and butter stuff.
好 我接下来会深入聊聊这些内容
Okay, I'm going to dig into a lot of that stuff.
你们最近做过的最聪明的一个增长动作之一 是把记忆导入这个点子
One of the cleverest growth moves y'all made recently was this idea of importing memory
就是从 ChatGPT 导入记忆 你们把这件事做得非常简单 顺势抓住了这个趋势
from ChatGPT, where you just made it really easy and kind of jumped on this trend of
人们对 Anthropic 感到非常兴奋
people getting really excited about Anthropic.
关于那个功能背后的故事你有没有什么可以分享的
Is there anything you could share about the behind the scenes story of that feature?
我当时在想我们能做些什么来改善冷启动问题并提升新用户体验
I was thinking about what can we do to improve the cold start problem and improve the new user experience?
我认为激活在 AI 领域是一个非常大的挑战
I think that activation is a really big challenge in AI.
所以那就是一个例子是我们在特定时间点上线的一个功能
And so that's one example of something that we shipped that was very specific to a moment in time.
但归根结底如果你把视角拉远
But ultimately, if you zoom out,
问题就变成了好我们到底如何让刚注册的人更容易
it's like, okay, how do you really make it easier for people who are signing up to have
让 Claude 了解他们是谁了解 Claude 能如何帮助他们并把他们引导到正确的地方
Claude understand who they are and understand how Claude can help them and get them to the right place?
我想顺着这个话题继续聊激活
I want to follow that thread, activation.
我在和负责推动 AI 产品增长的人聊天时经常会谈到一件事
There's something that comes up a ton when I talk to people leading driving growth on AI products.
现在有太多东西在争夺人们的注意力
It's just like, there are so much stuff trying to get your attention these days for people
要让人们走到那一步
to get to a place where they,
觉得好哇这真的是一个我想持续使用的东西
okay, wow, this is really going to be something I want to keep using.
事实证明这非常难
It proves to be really hard.
而且也很不稳定
And it's also just unreliable.
有时候它并不会那么神奇
Sometimes it's not going to be magical.
这是 AI它是非确定性的
It's AI. It's non-deterministic.
我想第一点就是
I guess one is just like,
专注于激活到底有多重要
how important is focusing on activation,
也就是让人们在 AI 产品上体验到那个恍然大悟的时刻
getting people to that aha moment with AI products?
第二你在如何通过 Claude 或更广义上的 AI 做好这件事方面有哪些经验教训
And two, what are some things you've learned about how to do that well with Claude or AI in general?
嗯这是个好问题
Yeah, it's a good question.
我认为激活是至关重要的对吧
I think that activation, it's critical, right?
而且这里指的是早期激活
And defining that as early activation,
也就是所谓第零天第一天的产品体验
call it day zero, day one product experience.
从历史上看
I think that historically,
任何做过增长或做过产品的人都明白那通常是
anyone who's been in growth or been in product understands that that's usually one of the
提升长期留存率最有力的杠杆之一
highest levers that you have to actually even increase longer term retention.
而且我认为它的重要性已经变得指数级地更高了
And I think that the importance of that has just gotten exponentially higher.
现在再把视角拉远我觉得行业里最大的问题之一是能力
Now, zooming out, I feel like one of the biggest problems in the industry is capability
溢出也就是模型进步得太快
overhang, where the models are just getting better so quickly.
真正的挑战在产品端是我们如何开始把这些好处扩散给用户
And the real challenge is on the product side of how do we start to diffuse those benefits to people?
甚至在公司内部也不断有新模型出现
Where even internally, there's new models coming internally,
而你忙得不可开交
and you're sitting there, you're so busy.
当一个新模型可用了
And when a new model's available,
你得硬挤出时间去想
you need to really carve out time to be like,
这个模型能做什么
what can this do?
我该如何更新自己的先验认知
How do I need to update my priors?
如果你把视角放到大多数人身上
And if you think about more broadly for most people,
你可能已经有了一个模型
you may have a model that is like,
你可能已经有 AGI 或某种能做各种惊人事情的模型
you may have AGI or some model that can do all sorts of crazy things.
但如果人们的本能是跑来只会问一句
But if people's instinct is to come there and be like,
嘿旧金山天气怎么样
hey, what's the weather in SF?
那他们就不可能最大化地利用这个产品
Then they're not going to get the most out of the product.
所以我觉得这很难因为模型能力提升得太快了
And so I think that it's tough because the model capabilities are rising so much.
所以如果我回想一下
So if I think about, okay,
比如当时我们只有我也不知道
back when we had, I don't know,
比如 Opus 4那时模型能做一系列事情
say like Opus 4, there's a series of things the model can do at that point.
而 Opus 4.5 又解锁了一大堆新能力
And Opus 4.5 unlocked a whole bunch of new things.
你会想，好吧，我们坐在那里，手上有了这个新模型
You think about, okay, we sit there, we've got this new model,
接下来要花时间去跑一堆测试
Opus 4, the time to then go and run a bunch of tests,
弄清楚好这个新模型有哪些能力
figure out, okay, there's the capabilities from this new model.
什么样的引导路径最适合把用户带到这些功能上
What are the right on ramps to guide people to those features?
你跑完测试得到一些经验
You run tests, you get the learnings,
然后上线一个新的流程
you then ship a new flow.
等你做完这些可能下一个模型已经出来了
By then you may already have the next model,
它又解锁了更新的能力让之前的这些经验都不再适用对吧
which unlocks newer capabilities that makes all these learnings irrelevant, right?
要在这上面始终保持领先其实是个非常难的问题
It's actually just like a really difficult problem to stay on top of.
我认为很多老的东西
I think that many of the same things,
也就是增长和激活里的那些老趋势依然是有效的
same old trends in growth and activation remain, I think, accurate.
但在我看来
But to me, it's like,
归根结底，最高的杠杆往往来自为合适的用户找到合适的产品或合适的功能
ultimately, some of the highest leverage is from finding the right product or the right feature for the right user.
我觉得有一个经验
And I think that one learning,
在各家公司一再被验证
you've seen this time and time again across companies,
其实合适的摩擦是有帮助的
actually, the right friction helps.
如果方式得当增加一些摩擦通常是有效的
And adding more friction usually works if you do it the right way.
这是我一直反复看到的在这里我们也看到了同样的情况
I think that's something I've consistently seen that we've seen here as well.
所以在我看来关键在于识别出一个用户具有什么特征
So to me, I think it's really being able to identify what are the characteristics of a
以便你能把他们推荐到合适的功能或产品上
user that allows you to then recommend them to the right feature or product.
而且在为此增加一些摩擦时不要畏首畏尾
And not being shy about adding friction to do that,
我认为这可能是这里最重要的一件事
I think, is probably the single biggest thing that's important here.
当我问 Ben Mann 的时候
When I asked Ben Mann,
他是联合创始人之一也是之前的播客嘉宾
one of the co-founders, former podcast guest,
问他我该问你什么
what to ask you about,
他特别强调的就是你的经验尤其是在 Mercury 的经历
and this is what he highlighted is your experience, especially at Mercury,
重新设计 onboarding 并把它做得非常神奇
redoing onboarding and making it magical.
总体来说他和你的看法一致都认为让人们
And basically, he's in the same place as you of just how important it is for people to
了解 AI 工具的能力有多重要这能帮助他们决定是否使用并坚持用下去
understand what the AI tool is capable of to help people decide to use it and stick with it.
能不能举个例子说说你在 onboarding 里做了什么改动显著提升了激活
Is there an example of something you changed in onboarding that helped significantly improve activation?
嗯这是个非常非常好的问题
Yeah, it's a great, great question.
我也很高兴他提到了 Mercury
And I like that he brings up Mercury.
我经常谈到他们的产品
I talk about their product a lot.
我之前在 Mercury 的增长团队工作过
So I've worked on the growth team at Mercury.
我认为那是一个非常出色的产品
I think it's a fantastic product.
很多人都在用它
It's something many people use.
人们使用它的原因是它提供了更好的银行体验
And the reason they use it is because it's a better banking experience.
是的我自己也是一个非常满意的用户顺便说一下
Yeah, I'm a very happy customer just with it out there.
这是个很棒的产品
It's a great product.
强烈推荐他们现在也有个人银行业务
Highly recommend it. They have it in personal banking.
每个人都应该去用用看
Everyone should go and use it.
对他们刚刚上线了这个
Right. They just launched that.
所以我觉得 Mercury 有趣的一点在于它的核心价值就是体验更好对吧
And so I think the interesting thing about Mercury is the core value is that it's a better experience, right?
这就是你使用它的原因
That's the reason you use it.
你并不是在别的方面得到什么更好的东西
You're not getting better other things.
只是它的产品体验更好
It's just it's a better product experience.
所以这种理念在公司内部
And so that ethos is very,
被非常深刻地坚持着
very deeply held within the company.
这源自几位创始人
It comes from a number of the founders.
我记得我在那里的时候有一个季度我们在入职培训流程上做了大力度的推进
And I think that we had a big push one quarter when I was there on the onboarding flow.
对于银行机构和受监管实体来说入职培训流程极其复杂
So onboarding flows for banking institutions and regulated entities are extremely complex.
比如我花了大量时间去搞清楚注册代理人地址
Like the amount of time I've spent on the difference between a registered agent address
和法律地址以及实际地址之间的区别
and a legal address and a physical address.
这些东西都非常非常复杂
These things are very, very complex.
然后我们基本上是看着这套入职培训流程在想
And we basically looked at the onboarding flow and we were like,
好我们在产品的其他部分已经在质量上投入了这么多
OK, we've invested so much in quality in the rest of the product,
但在这里其实还没有做到位
but we haven't really done it here.
可这是用户接触到的第一个体验
And this is the first experience that people have.
所以我们说先别管指标
And so we said, forget metrics,
别管增长别管其他一切
forget growth, forget everything else.
作为负责转化的增长团队
As the growth team on conversion,
我们要花整整一个季度来提升这条流程的质量
we're going to spend a whole quarter fixing quality in this flow.
所以那段时间我们就只做这一件事
And so that's all we do.
不看任何指标我们就是要把体验做到尽可能好把所有这些问题修掉比如
Forget the metrics. We're just going to make this as good of an experience as we can and fix all these like
你在不同字段之间来回跳转还要填写你的实益所有权细节信息
you go back from one field to the other field and adding in your beneficial ownership details.
结果事实证明
And it actually ended out being like,
直到我加入这里之前
and probably until I joined here,
这大概是我做增长以来在
like the single most impactful quarter that I've ever had as a growth team in terms of the
影响力上最有成效的一个季度
impact that it had.
所以我们看到从入职培训开始到完成的整个流程
And so we saw a significant uplift from basically our onboarding started to completion
仅仅因为专注于质量就有了显著提升
from just focusing on quality.
对我来说这是一个更广泛的认知就是质量会驱动增长我觉得
And so that to me is like a broader learning around quality drives growth that I think
我一直在努力把这一点带到 Anthropic 来
I've tried to bring to Anthropic.
I think for us at Anthropic,
我觉得在 Anthropic 这边
在入职培训流程上我们做的一些事情基本上是
you know, some of the things that we've done in the onboarding flow is basically like we
向用户提问他们是谁
ask users questions around who they are,
他们的兴趣领域是什么
what their interest areas are.
然后我们用这些信息来推荐不同的产品和功能
And we then use that to recommend different products and features.
有不少人看了这套流程之后会说
And like a number of people look at the flow and they're like,
你们的摩擦太多了
you have so much friction.
这个流程太长了
It's such a long flow.
而我会说我们有数据
And I'm like, we have the data.
我们对它目前的表现还是比较满意的
We're kind of happy with how it's performing.
你对摩擦的整体看法是什么
What is your kind of a philosophy on friction,
好的摩擦和坏的摩擦之间的区别是什么
good friction versus bad friction?
在我做增长的每一份工作里我一次又一次看到
I've just seen time and time again at every job I've been in in growth that adding
增加摩擦增加正确的步骤会带来更高的转化和更高的漏斗完成率
friction and adding the right steps leads to higher conversion and higher funnel completion.
所以你要去除的是
So you want to get rid of,
尤其是在量很大的情况下
especially if you have high volume,
你应该对大部分东西做测试去学习去观察
you should test the majority of this and just learn and see like,
这些结论是不是也适用于你的业务
does this apply to your business as well?
但你要去掉那些既烦人又不创造价值的摩擦
But you want to get rid of annoying friction that doesn't add value.
但我觉得大家最简单直观的理解是
But I think the most simple understanding people have is like,
只要缩短实现价值的时间
just solve time to value,
把所有步骤都砍掉直接把用户带进产品里
cut all the steps and just get them into the product.
而大多数时候这是行不通的
And that doesn't work most times.
如果你真的把自己的流程做了充分测试
If you've really thoroughly tested your flows,
我会回头看我待过的公司比如 MasterClass
I look at the companies I've been at, Masterclass.
如果你现在走一遍 MasterClass 的购买流程
If you go through Masterclass's purchase flow right now,
你会在打算购买时先经历一整套问答步骤
you will go through all these steps in this quiz when you land on when you're trying to buy.
你会觉得我就是来买东西的结果还要被问一堆问题
And it's like, I came here to buy and it's taking me through all these questions.
比如你来这里是为了什么之类的
What are you here for, etc.
很容易一看就觉得
I think it's easy to look at that and be like,
他们为什么要搞这些
why do they have this?
这看起来很糟糕
This is like a terrible thing.
全都砍掉就好了
Just cut it all.
但其实不是那一整套流程是经过充分测试的
And it's like, no, that's been thoroughly tested.
而且那实际上是一个重要的收入驱动因素因为它能让用户感觉到
And actually, that was like a significant revenue driver because it helps users feel that
产品是为他们量身打造的通过了解他们的兴趣再去推荐
the product is for them by understanding what their interests are and then recommending
相应的内容和课程
the content and classes there.
我们团队里有一位增长产品经理后来离职去了 Calm
One of the growth PMs on our team left to join Calm,
就是 Calm.com 那个冥想应用
Calm.com, the meditation app.
如果你去 Calm 的落地页走一遍他们的购买流程
If you go to Calm's landing page and you go through their purchase flow,
还有登录流程你也会看到一套问答
their login flow, you'll see a quiz.
这不是巧合
It's not a coincidence.
在 Mercury 我们也做过测试
At Mercury, we also tested,
I think Ahmad posted on Twitter,
我记得 Ahmad 还在 Twitter 上发过
我们把入职培训中的一些步骤拆开不再只用一个页面
we broke out some steps in onboarding and just having one screen.
如果你有五六个不同的表单输入项通常把它拆成两个页面
If you have like five or six different form inputs and you often break that into two
能降低用户的认知负担
screens and reduce the cognitive load to people,
这种做法的表现往往很好
that is something that performs well.
我们在那里的流程里增加了一些步骤结果表现确实不错
We added steps into the flow there that actually performed well.
在 Anthropic 也是如此所以对我来说结论是当摩擦没有提升体验时就应该去掉
Same at Anthropic. So I think that the takeaway to me is cut friction when it doesn't add to the experience
尤其是没有帮助用户理解为什么这个产品适合他们的时候
of helping a user understand why the product is for them.
但如果你能帮助用户理解一个产品
But if you can help users understand a product,
为什么这个产品适合他们怎么用以及什么对他们最相关
why a product is for them and how to use it and what's most relevant to them,
即便这会增加摩擦
and it's going to add friction,
也不要退缩
don't shy away from it.
要做测试确认它对你是有效的
Test it, confirm that it works for you.
不过我觉得大多数增长从业者对这一点都有很深的理解
But I think this is something that most growth practitioners deeply understand.
而其中“适合他们”这点真的非常关键
And the for them is really important there.
你刚才描述的是通过增加摩擦更好地了解用户是谁从而知道
What you described is adding friction to better understand who they are so that you know
要如何给他们推荐合适的东西
how to recommend the right thing for them.
没错是的而且如果做得好它会自然贯穿整个链路
Correct. Yes. And that done right, it just flows through.
它会帮助你提升激活
So it helps you with activation,
之后也会帮助你做生命周期运营
but then it helps you with lifecycle.
你会更了解这些用户以及他们为什么会来
You know more about those users and why they're here.
而且大多数成熟的企业
And most sophisticated businesses,
即使有人中途流失
even if someone drops off,
也可以做相似人群定向在广告层面再把他们找回来
you can do lookalike targeting and you can get them at the ad layer as well.
所以一开始你如何理解用户是谁这部分信息
So that initial piece of how you understand who the user is,
如果在后续漏斗中用得好就会源源不断地产生价值
it's a juice that just keeps on giving if you then use it right for the down funnel.
接下来大家可能都会去拆解 Claude 的入职流程MasterClass 的入职流程还有 Mercury 的入职流程
Everyone's about to go do a bunch of teardowns of Claude's onboarding, Masterclass onboarding, Mercury onboarding.
稍微扯远一点
Kind of as a tangent,
我最近参加了一个产品经理的晚宴我在问所有的 PM
I was at this PM dinner recently and I was asking all the PMs,
在 AI 出现之后你作为 PM 的角色变化最大的是哪里
how has your role as a PM changed most with AI?
也就是 AI 对你日常工作的影响最大体现在什么地方
Like, where has AI most impacted what you do?
其中一位 PM 回答说其实是做竞品分析
And one of the PMs answered that is actually doing competitive analysis,
会大量拆解别人是如何设计定价页面和入职流程的
doing a bunch of like teardowns of what other people are doing for pricing pages and onboarding.
所以现在做这件事很容易
So it's easy to do now.
Just, hey, hey, Cowork.
就是，嘿，嘿，Cowork
我不确定，你会用 Cowork 来做这件事，还是用 Claude
I don't know, would you Cowork for this or Claude?
你会用什么工具来做这件事
What would you use for that?
好的，这个不错
Okay, this is good.
帮助人们选择该用哪个工具
Help people pick which tool to use.
如果你想去拆解一堆其他竞争对手的入职培训流程
If you want to go do a bunch of teardowns of other competitors onboarding flows,
你会用什么呢？你可以用 Cowork 来做这件事，对吧
what would you use? You can use Cowork for this, right?
So you have Cowork with the Chrome extension.
所以你有带 Chrome 插件的 Cowork
所以如果你给带 Chrome 插件的 Cowork 下任务
So if you task Cowork with the Chrome extension,
让它去找这些流程并展示给我看
go and look for these flows and show me,
给我一个视图，告诉我哪些有效，哪些无效
give me a view of what's working, what's not.
这绝对是 Cowork 能做到的事情
That's definitely something that Cowork can do.
很好。我想这就是其中一个挑战
Cool. I imagine that's one of the challenges,
你现在有这么多工具
you have all these tools now,
只是到底哪个适合我
just which one's for me?
顺便说一下，那个 Chrome 插件
By the way, the Chrome extension,
我一直在用
I use it all the time.
它非常棒。我想再深入聊一下增长团队
It's amazing. I want to drill a little bit further into the growth org.
前几天在 Twitter 上有个梗
There was this whole meme on Twitter the other day of just like,
说 Anthropic 所有的增长都是一个增长营销在撑着
you have one growth marketer driving all growth at Anthropic.
大家就觉得，哇，这也太夸张了
And it's like, okay, that's crazy.
你们现在有多少增长相关的人
How many growth people are there?
增长团队大致的组织结构是怎样的
What's kind of the rough org structure of the growth team?
我们现在大概有 40 个人左右
We're roughly maybe 40 people now.
所以我们，我觉得
And so we are, I think,
结构上非常像一个传统的增长团队，因为我们有一些横向职能
structured very much like a traditional growth team in that we have sort of horizontals of
比如增长平台和变现
growth platform and monetization.
我们会从整个产品线的角度来思考增长的范围
We think about the sphere of growth across the entirety of our products.
然后我们还有更多面向特定受众的增长小组
And then we have more sort of audience-focused growth pods.
比如你可以理解为 B2B 增长
You can think about like B2B growth.
也可以理解为代码相关增长、知识工作者增长、API 增长
You can think about code growth, knowledge worker growth, API growth.
所以就是围绕这些受众来保持一个聚焦
So really like these audiences to keep a narrow focus,
当你有这么多不同产品时，这一点是必须要做的
which is the thing you have to do when you have so many different products.
然后这些横向团队会从全局来思考问题
And then these horizontals that sort of think about things across the board.
那这些团队里是工程师
And is it across a team of engineers,
设计师、产品经理都有吗，这个增长组织里都有哪些职能
designers, PMs, what's kind of like this functions within this growth org?
对，有工程师、设计师、产品经理，还有数据
Yeah, it's engineers, designers, PMs, data.
我觉得整体上
I think that overall,
这个组织的形态和
the shape of the org is quite similar to,
我会说，和一个传统的增长团队非常相似
I'd say, a traditional growth team.
可能不太一样的地方在于
Probably the things that are maybe different is that we,
我们更偏向于做大幅度的尝试，而不是小幅优化
I think that we index a lot more towards larger swings as opposed to smaller optimizations.
比如如果我回想一个传统的增长团队
Like if I think about a traditional growth team,
我可能会把 60-70% 的时间花在小到中等规模的下注上
I would have probably done maybe 60-70% of my time on small to medium bets,
然后 20-30% 放在更大的尝试上
20-30% on larger swings.
而对我们来说
And I think that for us,
这个比例几乎是反过来的
we flip it a lot.
我们更多是 70-30%，甚至更像 50-50%，而不是偏向小赌注
We do much more the other way where it's 70-30% or more like 50-50% rather than indexing towards smaller bets.
我觉得这可能是最大的变化之一
That's probably one of the biggest changes, I think.
为了强调这一点
Just to highlight that,
有趣的是，以你们现在的体量
what's interesting there is at the scale you guys are at,
1% 的提升在整体上已经是非常巨大的
a 1% win is massive in the scheme of things.
所以很有意思的是，即使在你们这个规模
So it's interesting that even at the scale you're at,
你们也没有把重点放在这些微小优化上
you're not focusing on these micro-optimizations.
其实很容易的，你完全可以专注在这些小优化上，然后在季度末把它们加总起来
It is easy. You could easily focus on these small optimizations and then you tally them up at the end of the quarter.
然后说，你看我们带来了多大的影响
And you're like, look how much impact we made.
你们是可以这么做的
And you could do that.
又多了十亿，没什么大不了的
Another billion. No big deal.
是。但问题在于，我们一直在实现每年 10 倍的增长
Yeah. But the thing is, we've been tracking at 10x year on year.
这是我们始终记在心里的事
And that's the thing that we keep in mind.
我觉得归根结底，是因为这家公司对指数级变化有一种执念
And I think it ultimately comes down to our fixation at this company about the exponential.
如果你看 Anthropic 里任何一个人在谈几乎任何话题
I think if you look at anyone who's talking from Anthropic about basically anything,
我们总是在谈指数级
we always talk about the exponential.
实际上，随着模型能力持续指数级提升，以及围绕它们的工具
Effectively, as model capabilities continue to grow on an exponential and the tools around
能更好地把这些能力扩散到有用的应用场景中
them enable a better job of diffusing that into useful use cases,
你基本上会不断解锁新的市场，而这些市场的价值
you basically just keep unlocking new markets where the value of those markets
会远远超过之前那些市场的价值
significantly dwarfs what the value of the previous markets were.
具身智能编码就是一个很好的例子
And agentic coding is a great example.
在一年前、一年半前它还不存在
It didn't exist a year, a year and a half ago.
而现在，具身智能编码本身的价值就已经超过了之前 AI 编码市场的价值
And then now just the value of agentic coding is bigger than the previous market AI coding use.
所以我认为这里的核心在于
And so I think that is the core thing here,
未来产品的价值会比今天高出一个数量级
which is that the future product value is an order of magnitude higher than it is today.
然后我会去想，我不知道
And I think about, I don't know,
对于一个普通的业务来说
like a normal business,
比如我之前提到过的一些公司
number of companies that I've maybe mentioned,
或者你可以想象一个交易应用，或者一个生鲜配送产品
or you can think about a trading app or a grocery delivery product.
许多头部公司本身都是很好的生意
Many of the leading companies are great businesses.
但如果我去想，一个公司
But if I think about what is the product value that a company,
比如一个标准的、生鲜配送类应用
like a standard, like call it a grocery delivery app,
作为终端用户，你今天从这个产品获得的价值，和两年后相比会怎样
what is the product value you get as an end user today versus two years from now?
我是这样看的，就好比说，再过两年
I look at it as like, again, two years from now,
即使你不断上线各种新产品，作为终端用户
even if you're shipping all these new products as an end user,
你从这个产品获得的价值，可能会提升 30% 到 50%，前提是公司在
the value you get from that product maybe goes up like 30 to 50% if the company's done a
上线新功能这件事上做得非常好
really good job of shipping new features.
但这并不是指数级的
It's not exponential though.
所以如果我去想
And so if I think about,
好，你现在在这个点
okay, you're here today,
两年后，你的产品价值会提升 30% 到 50%
in two years, you're going to have 30 to 50% more product value.
那么作为一个增长团队
Then as a growth team,
未来两年产品价值相对今天的差额
the like relative differential of the product value two years from now relative to today,
我其实可以通过那些小到中等规模的优化
I can actually capture like a decent percentage of that with the small to medium
把其中相当一部分吃下来，而且这些优化通常比大赌注更有把握
optimizations that typically have higher conviction as opposed to like larger bets.
但对 Anthropic 来说情况并不是这样，因为指数级变化，以及我们的
But for Anthropic, it's not really that way where because of the exponential and our
产品是那种非常
products being like very,
非常非常依赖 AI 带来价值的产品
very, very, the product value coming from AI,
我们在两年后能交付的产品价值，很可能会是现在的 1000 倍
the product value that we will deliver in two years time is probably like 1000x,
是今天的 100 到 1000 倍
100 to 1000x what it is today.
所以如果我想到这一点
And so if I think about that,
就会觉得眼前有巨大的价值空间
and it's like, there's so much value on offer,
你就需要更多地转向一种思路
you need to shift more towards,
好，我们需要下更大的赌注
okay, we need to take larger bets,
而且我们不能只盯着细枝末节而忽略整体格局
and we need to not sort of miss the forest for the trees.
这也是为什么我们依然会做各种小优化，这些确实很重要
And so that's why we still do all the small optimizations, it really matters.
而且有些事情不会有别人来替我们做
And like no one else is going to do some of these things.
所以我们必须自己去做
And so we need to do it.
这些复利式的价值绝不是无足轻重的
The compounding value is not immaterial,
但与此同时我们也会在核心产品层面做更大幅度的尝试
but we do take on much larger core product-y type of swings as well.
你刚才提到那个 Chrome 扩展
So you mentioned that the Chrome extension,
现在它已经成为 Cowork 和 Claude Code 上很多用例的底层支撑
like that is now the thing that underpins a number of use cases on Cowork and Claude Code as well.
而那是由增长团队打造的东西
And that's something that the growth team built.
那是一个非常“AI 上头”的产品，也是一个高度依赖研究的产品
That's like a very like AI-pilled product that is like a very research-heavy product that
我们当时就是非常看好它
we were just bullish on it.
我们有一位工程师对它特别看好
We had an engineer who was very bullish on it,
然后我们的想法就是
and we were just like,
嘿，没有别人在做这件事
hey, no one else is doing it,
那就由我们来做
we're going to do it.
这种事如果在别的公司，我是不会去做的
And so that's the sort of thing that I wouldn't have done at another company.
哦，哇，这个……我之前完全不知道
Oh, wow, that's... I did not know that.
所以这里有一个结论可以提炼出来
So the takeaway, one takeaway here is like,
你的很多建议里有些东西只在 Anthropic 这种环境下才成立
you know, there's like stuff to extract from your advice that is like only true at Anthropic.
另外一部分则是其他公司可以从你的这些经验中学到什么
And then there's what can other companies learn from this experience that you've had?
那么其中一点是，你是不是觉得如果你在做 AI
So one is, is your sense that if you're working in AI,
就应该把更多资源从饼图里划给那些更大的赌注
shift more of the pie chart towards bigger bets?
因为在未来
Because in the future,
机会会大到这种程度
the opportunity is so large,
你会更想尽快找到这些机会，而不是只做微小优化
you want to find those as soon as possible versus micro-optimize?
更具体一点说
To be more specific there,
我会说，如果你的产品所提供的主要价值是由 AI 作为
I'd say that if the primary value that your product delivers is underpinned by AI as a
其中的核心要素来支撑的
central element of it,
那我认为你就应该按这种方式来运作
then I think you should operate this way.
比如说，像 Lovable 这样的公司
So I don't know, companies like Lovable,
Cursor 之类的，这些很优秀的业务
Cursor, you know, all these like great businesses that are like,
随着指数级曲线往上走
it's as the exponential rises,
它们的价值主张也会显著同步提升
their value props are also going to continue to rise significantly.
换句话说，如果你在做的是一个 AI 优先的产品
Like if you're building a product where it's like it's an AI first product,
那我肯定会用这种方式来运营
then I would definitely operate in this way.
但如果你做的产品并不一定是 AI 优先
I think if you're building a product where it's not necessarily an AI first product,
只是旁边带了一些 AI 功能
and you have some AI features that are on the side,
但那并不是你价值的核心
but it's not the core of your value,
那我就不一定会用这种方式来做
I don't know that I would operate this way.
这会取决于你产品其他部分的人员配置，以及增长团队相对它是怎么配置的
It would depend on how is the rest of the product staffed and how is the growth staffed in relation to that.
好的，太棒了 那在组织结构方面
Okay, awesome. And then in terms of the way you're structured,
我觉得非常有意思
I thought that was really interesting.
它像是由不同类型的东西组合在一起
It's like a combination of different sorts of things.
比如有 API 增长
So there's like the API growth,
有Claude Code的增长，但也还有类似人格之类的东西
there's Claude Code growth, but then there's also like personas,
比如知识型工作者和 B2B 这样的垂直方向
like a vertical of like knowledge workers and B2B.
这是刻意设计的吗 就是一部分是针对性的下注，另一部分是面向更广阔市场机会
Is that intentional? Like some specific bets and the one just kind of like broad market opportunity?
当你只有一个产品的时候
When you have like one product,
会更容易把增长团队纯粹围绕漏斗来组织，对吧
it's easier to have a growth team that's more like purely on the funnel, right?
比如你有转化
It's like you have the conversion,
有激活，有变现
you have activation, you have monetization.
但当你开始拥有多个产品时
But as you start to get into having multiple products,
我觉得就会变难，因为如果你还那样组织
I think that's harder because if you do that,
比如你只有一个激活团队
then if you just have like one activation team,
for example, but then you have Claude Code,
但你同时又有 Claude Code
有 Cowork，还有其他一堆东西
you have Cowork, you have all the other things.
它们面向的受众完全不同
They're very different audiences,
而且在公司内部对应的跨职能干系人也完全不同
and they're very different sets of cross-functional stakeholders internally.
所以我们会去思考
So we're kind of looking at what is the thing,
任何组织结构都不完美
and all structures are like not perfect,
它们只是在某个时间点是合适的
and they're like right for a point in time.
但我们在寻找一种结构，能让我们尽可能聚焦
But we're looking for what is the structure that allows us to have as much focus,
聚焦这件事非常重要
like focus is a really big thing,
无论是对目标受众还是对要解决的问题
and on audience and problems,
同时和跨职能合作伙伴之间的衔接也极其重要
and also the tie-ins to cross-functional partners is really, really important.
比如我们 Claude Code 增长团队里的同事
Like the folks in our Claude Code growth team,
他们会和 Kat、Boris 以及那个团队里的其他人高度紧密地合作
they work extremely closely with Kat and Boris and the others on that team.
所以这种紧密衔接本身也非常关键
And so that tie-in is really important as well.
你在很多不同的公司都做过增长
So you've done growth at a lot of different companies,
在加入 Anthropic 之前，基本都是我们可以称之为传统增长的那一套
a lot of basically let's call it traditional growth before Anthropic.
随着 AI 的兴起，作为一个职能和一套技能体系的增长
How else is growth as a function and as a skill set changing with the rise of AI,
在 AI 产品和 AI 创业公司里还发生了哪些变化
AI products, AI startups?
我认为如果你的核心产品价值高度依赖 AI 支撑
I think if your core product value is very backed by AI,
那么你会越来越倾向于做更大的下注，而不是做小到中等规模的实验
then it is shifting where you're skewing more towards larger bets as opposed to smaller medium experiments.
在其他方面
I think in other things,
有件和此相关的大事，我觉得会加速这一趋势
it may be a big thing related to this that I think will accelerate this,
我也非常好奇它最终会如何发展
which I am really interested to see how it will play out,
就是我们开始探索如何把增长自动化
is we are starting to look at how do we automate growth,
我认为这是一个非常有趣的领域
which I think is like a really interesting area.
我们的增长平台团队非常幸运
Our growth platform team, we're very lucky.
We have Alexei Komissarov,
因为我们有 Alexei Komissarov
他在 Reforge 教授增长工程
who teaches growth engineering at Reforge,
而且他就是团队里的那个关键人物
and he's just like the guy on the team.
所以是他在主导这项工作
And so he is driving this effort.
这个名字有点让人尴尬
The name is a little cringy.
不是我起的
I didn't come up with it.
And it's called CASH, which is Claude Accelerates Sustainable Hypergrowth.
它被称为CASH，全称是Claude Accelerates Sustainable Hypergrowth
这个名字真的不是我起的
I did not come up with that.
但本质上，这是在探索如何用 Claude 来自动化增长实验
But really, it's an effort to look at how can we use Claude to automate growth experimentation.
目前规模还非常非常小
And it is still very, very small.
也还处在非常非常早期的阶段
It's still very, very early.
我们启动这个项目也只是
We kicked it off only,
大概几个月之前的事
I think, a couple of months ago.
我认为在 Opus 4.5 之前
I think before Opus 4.5,
这其实是做不到的
it wasn't really possible.
我们就是看不到任何结果
We were just like not seeing the results.
而最近随着 Opus 4.6 的推出
And more recently with Opus 4.6,
我们会觉得，好的，这好像是在朝着正确的方向前进
we're like, okay, this is like headed in the right direction.
所以我认为这件事
And so this, I think,
基本上会在整个行业里越来越普遍地发生
will happen more and more across the industry where basically,
如果你想一想
if you think about, okay,
我觉得这可以发生在整个产品领域
I think this can happen all across product,
但尤其是在增长团队里
but growth teams in particular,
因为有一整块工作都是做非常细微的优化
because there's this whole body of work that is very small optimizations,
我认为它们在本质上更适合更早去应对这类事情
I think are just more inherently suited to tackle this earlier.
如果你去思考一下一个功能上线的生命周期
I think if you think about the life cycle of shipping,
大致可以分成四个部分
there's this sort of four parts to it.
第一是识别机会
One is identifying opportunities,
比如 Claude 基于不同趋势来真正识别机会的能力有多强
like how good is Claude at actually identifying opportunities based on different trends,
基于 Claude 过去见过的那些历史趋势
based on previous trends that Claude has seen in the past.
第二是真正把功能做出来并准备好上线
Second is then building the actual feature and getting it ready to ship.
第三是测试并确保它符合你的质量标准和品牌标准
Third is testing and ensuring that it meets your quality bar and your brand bar.
第四是当你真正把东西上线之后
And then fourth is then once you've actually shipped the thing,
分析数据并总结经验
analyzing the data, gathering the learnings.
如果你把这看作一个循环
If you think about that as like the loop of,
好，这四件事你都可以做评估，并在每个环节上不断爬坡优化
okay, these are four things that you can eval and he'll climb on each of these areas and
来了解模型在这些环节里到底帮你做得有多好
understand how good is a model doing for you there.
我们基本上就是按这四个维度来思考
And we basically think about it in that like the four ways.
然后给 Claude 在每个环节的表现打分
And we are scoring how good is Claude doing in each of those areas.
所以目前我们是在相当小的规模上做这些测试
And so we've been testing this with pretty small scale right now.
大多是文案修改和一些非常细微的 UI 调整
It's been a lot of copy changes and some like very minor UI tweaks.
它确实在带来结果
It's delivering results, right?
而且你可以不断推动它
And it's like, you can push it,
就像按下播放键一样让它跑起来
press play with it.
最终它就是在“印钞”，但我会说它的胜率大概是
It ultimately prints money where I'd say that the win rate is like,
我会预期一个资深产品经理能做得更好
I would expect a senior PM to do better.
我会说如果把它当成一个初级产品经理
Like I would say like if this is like a junior PM,
大概有两三年经验
like two, three years in,
那我会觉得这就是我对一个初级产品经理所预期的胜率
I would say this is like the win rate that I would expect from a junior PM.
但它还没有达到资深产品经理的水平
But it's not quite at the senior PM level.
不过如果你从指数级的角度来看
Although I think like you look at the exponential,
几个月前这些能力是完全不存在的
this wasn't available at all a couple of months ago.
所以它在快速变好
So it's getting better rapidly.
我认为接下来会发生变化，你将能在更大规模上
And I think that it's going to change where you'll be able to do this for larger and
做越来越大的实验
larger types of experiments.
但当你想到那些最大型的实验时
But then you think about the largest types of experiments,
我刚才提到的那四个环节：识别机会
I think that I mentioned the four pieces around identifying opportunities,
构建、测试和上线
building, testing, and shipping.
有一个我没提到的
The one I didn't mention there,
Lenny，就是跨职能的利益相关方管理
Lenny, is cross-functional stakeholder management.
这块仍然需要人类的大脑
There's still a need for human brains.
就在这里。而我认为正因为这一点，在我看来
There it is. And I think that that one is going to mean that in my eyes,
产品经理这份工作在短期内其实不会消失
the work of PMs is not going away actually anytime soon.
而这一部分，尤其是在大型项目中
And that piece, especially for larger projects,
对于小项目你不需要做那么多，对吧
you don't need to do as much of it for smaller stuff, right?
你可以略过很多
You can skip it.
但对大项目来说
But for larger stuff,
这一块是不会消失的
that piece is not going away.
除非其他利益相关方也都变成各自跑来跑去的小智能体
Until the other stakeholders are their own little agents running around.
我觉得没错
I think that's right.
我认为那会是局面真正改变的时刻
I think that would be the point where it changes.
有趣的是，几周前我们开了一个很艰难的会
It's funny, we had a difficult meeting a couple of weeks ago.
我跟我们的设计负责人
And me and our head of design,
Joel，会后在复盘
Joel, we were debriefing afterwards.
然后他给我发消息，说
And he pings me, he's just like,
Amol，就算我们有了 AGI，要让六个人坐在一个房间里达成一致仍然是不可能的
Amol, we will have AGI and it will still be impossible to get six people in a room to get to align.
我当时就说，是啊，我觉得
And I'm like, yeah, I think that's,
这完全说得通
I can see that.
这就像是在问，还有什么比这更难的对齐问题吗
That's a, like, what's the harder alignment problem?
哦，好的，这太有意思了
Oh, okay. This is so interesting.
而且这正是我觉得事情在发展的方向
And this is exactly where I feel like things are going.
为了说清楚，你刚才分享的内容是
So just to be clear, what you shared here,
基本上有一个工具会提出要做哪些实验，来帮助推动 Claude 以及所有这些工具的增长
there's basically this tool that comes up with experiments to run to help grow Claude and all the tools.
它先提出想法
So it comes up with idea,
然后有人过目
somebody looks at them,
批准，说好，那我们就做这些
proves, cool, let's do these things,
接着把功能做出来、上线、测试结果
builds it, ships it, tests the results,
看看表现如何
see how it's doing.
然后它再反馈回来
And then it comes back like,
告诉你哪些东西是有效的
here's things that are working.
大致是这样吗
Is that roughly right?
大致是这样，而且目前我们在审批环节仍然有人在链路里
It's roughly right. And like we, right now we have human in the loop approving.
但是在花费时间这件事上
But like the amount of time,
我会这样看待规模化：每一周
I kind of think about scale in this way of just like week on week,
各个环节是不是都在变好
are things getting better in each of the areas?
人们在每个环节上花的时间是不是在减少
Are people spending less time on each of the areas?
这些环节的结果是不是在变好
Are the results getting better into the areas?
只要每一周
And as long as like week on week,
这些都在变好，你就会觉得
that's getting better than you're like,
好，这整个项目确实在规模化推进
okay, this whole initiative is like scaling.
所以大致情况就是这样
And so that's roughly right.
但你也可以这样来看
But you can think about it as,
我认为很多地方其实可以自动化，不再需要人工审核
I think a lot of this can be automated where human review is not needed.
我们非常在意品牌，对吧
So we care a lot about brand, right?
所以这一点目前还是要人工把关
So that is something that we do look at right now.
我们不希望上线任何违背品牌调性的东西
We don't want to be shipping something that goes against the brand.
但接下来，你可以有一个技能，里面包含你的品牌规范以及非常
But then, you know, you can have a skill that contains your brand guidelines and very
明确的品牌该做与不该做的事项
clear yet do's and don'ts on brand.
所以所有这些配套的东西
And so all of these types of like accompaniments,
我认为都会变得更好
I think are going to get better.
模型也会更擅长理解如何使用它们
The model is going to get better at understanding how to use them.
所以随着时间推移，我认为对这类内容进行人工审核的需求会大幅下降
And so over time, I think that the need to like human review this really, really decreases significantly.
是啊，而且如果真的出了问题，你随时可以把它下线
Yeah, and you could always unship it if it's like,
哦，是的，那其实并不是一个好主意
oh, yeah, that was actually not a great idea.
而且你提到的这一点非常好，我们总是会觉得
And that's such a good point that we like,
我们好像需要人类永远来做这些事情
we think we need people to do these things forever.
结果发现，好吧
And it turns out, okay,
一项技能就能把这件事做得很好
a skill can do this really well.
这是我们的品牌规范
Here's our brand guidelines.
这是我们的愿景，这是我们的使命
Here's our vision. Here's our mission.
这是我们的目标，这是对我们来说重要的东西
Here's our goals. Here's what matters to us.
好，那我们就不要把那个东西上线
Okay, so let's not ship that thing.
我之所以觉得这件事这么有趣的原因是
So the reason I think this is so interesting,
这就好像，我一直在观察 AI 在产品开发流程中承担越来越多的部分
this is like, I've just been watching the expansion of AI doing more of the product development process.
在这个例子里，是在增长流程中
In this case, the growth process of just,
好吧，它从帮你写代码，到几乎写你所有的代码，再到帮你审查代码
okay, it went from helping you write code to like writing all your code to reviewing your code.
现在感觉像是在想，这条链路的另外两端是什么
Now, it feels like what are the other ends of this,
围绕这件事的两个端点
the two ends around this,
有点像是从中间向外扩展
it's kind of going from the middle out.
顶端是想清楚要做什么
The top of that is coming up with what to do.
然后还有对齐之类的事情，这部分依然非常难
And then there's like the alignment stuff still very hard.
然后在另一端
And then on the other end,
是审查代码并把它上线
it's reviewing the code and then shipping it.
然后获取分发能力这件事
And then get distribution is,
那又是我想单独和你聊的一整块内容
that's like a whole other thing I want to talk to you about.
所以我从这里听到的是
So what I'm hearing here,
而这也正是我之前预期会发生的事情，就是 AI 现在开始变得
and this is exactly what I thought was going to start happening is AI is now getting
非常擅长告诉我们该做什么
really good at telling us what to do,
而不仅仅是接受你的指令然后帮你做出来
not just taking your orders and building it.
而且感觉这一切会先从增长方向的版本开始
And it feels like the growth version of this is where it starts,
因为那部分要简单得多
because it's so much simpler,
不是说增长这件事本身很容易
just not that growth is easy,
而是因为它是数据驱动的
but just like it's data driven.
正如你刚才说的，它有一个完整的循环
There's this loop that you talked about.
所以我觉得这对整个产品领域未来的发展是一个非常有趣的信号
So I think this is such an interesting sign of things to come across just generally product.
对，没错，我只是把这个观点抛出来
Yeah, that's right. Just putting that out there.
好，那沿着这条线我一直在思考的一件事就是未来
Okay, so something that I'm constantly thinking about along these lines is just the future
产品、PM 和工程这三者
of product PM engineering,
这些角色会随着时间如何变化
how those roles shift over time,
基于我们刚才讨论的这些东西
based on the stuff we're talking about.
你们现在是如何作为一个三人组合协同工作的
How are you working together as a triad?
你觉得这些角色未来会走向哪里
And where do you see these roles going?
哪一部分会发生最大的变化
What's most going to change,
在这三个角色之间，你觉得会变动最大的是什么
do you think, across these three roles?
这是我们经常讨论和思考的问题
This is like something that we talk about and think about frequently,
而且这个图景变化得非常快
and the picture changes rapidly.
所以有时候当事情出了问题
So sometimes when things break and,
比如在执行层面出现瓶颈
you know, execution like the bottlenecks break,
过去在历史上
historically in the past,
通常就是，好，那你需要多招一些工程师
it's like, okay, now you need to hire more engineers,
多招一些设计师之类的
hire more designers, etc.
而这更多是一个生命周期上的问题
And it's more just like a life cycle thing of like,
看你的团队以及那个具体小组处在生命周期的哪个阶段，从而识别瓶颈在哪里
where is the life cycle of your team and that specific pod to identify where the bottleneck is.
但现在当事情出了问题时
But now when things break,
你仍然需要去看
you need to still look at it of like,
好，这到底是人员配比的问题吗
okay, is it like the actual ratio?
还是说底层的技术变革也在导致这些问题的出现
Or is there also underlying technological shifts that are also causing this to break?
所以这本身就是一件很有意思的事
And so that's like an interesting thing.
我觉得在小公司里
I think that smaller companies,
比如我在一家只有十五二十个人的公司
like if I'm at like a 15 or 20 person company,
我可能是唯一的 PM，和几个设计师、工程师一起工作
I'm like the only PM there working with some designers and engineers.
我觉得，在小公司里
I think, I think in the smaller companies,
你可能会看到角色混合得最厉害，PM 会做各种各样的事情
you'll see probably like the biggest blend where like the PM will be doing all sorts of,
比如设计、上线交付之类的
you know, designing, shipping, etc.
而我认为你会看到一种非常极端的分化
And I think you just have extreme bifurcation.
对于更大的组织、更大规模的公司来说
You know, larger organizations, more scaled organizations,
我觉得现在还远远没有定论
I think the jury is still very much out.
就算你在我们内部和不同的人聊
Like you speak to people even internally here,
不同团队、不同的人对这件事都有不同看法
and different people in different teams have different views of like,
这些角色会在多大程度上融合，或者在多大程度上保持分离
how much are these roles coming together versus how much are these roles going to be separate?
我并不是说
I think that it's not to say like,
就连 PM 也是，很多 PM 自己在负责上线、自己提 PR 之类的事情就不存在了
even the PMs, like a number of PMs are shipping and themselves shipping and pushing PRs, etc.
但如果我从整体上来看
But if I look at, okay,
结合我目前看到的情况
across what I'm seeing,
很明显，虽然 PM 和设计师都在从 AI 中获得更多杠杆
I think that it's clear that while PMs and designers are getting more leverage from AI,
但工程团队目前获得的杠杆是最大的
engineering is getting the most leverage right now.
我看像 Claude Code 这样的工具
I look at tools like Claude Code,
工程师从这些工具中获得的杠杆程度
and the amount of leverage engineers are getting from them is higher than I think the
要高于设计师和 PM 目前从中获得的杠杆
amount of the leverage that designers and PMs are getting from them today.
当然，这一点也在快速变化
Now, that's like rapidly also changing.
但这是我目前的看法
But that to me is like my view today.
所以如果你想一想
And so if you think about,
好，一个默认配置的团队
okay, a default team,
比如五个工程师
which is, say, five engineers,
一个设计师，一个 PM
one designer, one PM,
有了 Claude Code，那五个工程师的产能就像是放大到两三倍，对吧
with Claude Code, that five engineers is like two to three X, right?
PM 和设计师的产能也有所提升
And the PMs and designers have also increased,
但他们现在要管理的，实际上是一个大得多的工程师团队
but now they're managing what is effectively a much larger group of engineers.
所以即使人头数和组织结构没有变化
And so even though the headcount and the org structure hasn't changed,
你现在面对的情况，相当于在过去要管理十五到二十个工程师
you're now just dealing with a situation of maybe 15 to 20 engineers in the old world,
一点五到两个 PM
one and a half to two PMs,
以及大概一点五到两个设计师
and maybe one and a half to two designers.
所以我们看到这给 PM 和设计团队带来了很大的压力
And so we're seeing that that's putting a lot of strain on PM and design.
当然这并不是在所有地方都这样
And it's not everywhere.
比如我看像 Claude Code 这样的团队
I look at teams like Claude Code,
我觉得那个组织
and I think that org,
因为那个产品本身非常技术向
because that product is so technical,
所以 PM 本身基本都是工程师，这样的配置可能刚好是对的
it's probably just the right thing where the PMs are all basically engineers themselves anyway.
但我们前阵子有一位产品
But we had a product,
一位 PM 负责人来现场
a PM lead on site the other week,
我们大家就在聊这件事
and we were all just talking about this way.
整体上我们都有这样的感受
Across the board, we're feeling this way.
PM 和设计就是被挤压得很厉害
PM and design is just squeezed.
就是被彻底压榨到极致
It's just absolutely squeezed.
然后我们就在想，这样做到底是不是对的
And we're like, is the right thing here?
我们是不是真的需要再多招一大批产品经理
We just need to actually hire a ton more PMs.
而这可能真的是我们最后得出的结论
And that could actually be where we land.
关于增长，我的看法是
On growth, how I think about it is,
第一，我们正在招聘多名增长产品经理
one, we are hiring a number of growth PMs.
我们非常迫切地需要特别优秀的人才
We desperately need people who are very, very good.
而且我们现在就在招人
And we are hiring.
所以如果你对我们在做的事情感到兴奋，而且懂增长
So if you are excited by what we're doing and you know growth,
非常欢迎你来投简历
please feel free to apply.
我非常希望能和你聊聊
Would love to chat.
也许我会给你写一封超棒的冷邮件
Maybe craft an amazing cold email to you.
你也可以随意给我精心写一封邮件
Feel free to craft that email.
所以第一点是，我认为我们会招聘相当多的产品经理
So that's one, is I think we are going to be hiring a number of PMs.
第二点是，我们会大量招聘有产品思维的工程师
But then the second thing that we do is we very much hire product-minded engineers.
我认为在增长领域，这一直是最好的做法
I think this has always been the best thing to do in growth.
你总是希望工程师能不断提出想法等等
You always want to have the engineers coming up with ideas, etc.
尤其是那些在没有PM时能顶上去当“小PM”的人
And so especially people who can really step in as mini PMs if the PM is absent.
所以我们现在基本上是更正式地利用这一点，因为我们实在太吃紧了
And so we're basically more formally leveraging that right now because we are so stretched.
所以我们的框架是，如果一个项目需要的工程时间在两周或以内
So the frame that we have is that if a project is two weeks of engineering time or less,
那么工程师就要负责，等同于担任这个项目的PM
then the engineer is on the hook to effectively be the PM for that.
这就意味着要去和安全团队沟通
And so that means things like talking to security,
和法务沟通，和各个跨职能相关方沟通
talking to legal, talking to cross-functional stakeholders.
而工程师会真正主导这一切
And the engineer is very much driving that.
PM会被拉进来，在需要时提供建议
The PM will get looped in and they'll advise if needed.
如果事情严重偏离轨道
And if something is wildly going off track,
那他们就会介入
then they'll step in.
但他们更多是以顾问身份参与，而不是亲自执行
But they're much more in an advisory capacity versus execution.
如果一个项目超过两周的工程时间
If a project is more than two engineering weeks,
那默认就是由PM继续负责确保项目顺利推进
then the default is that the PM should continue to be on the hook for making that go well.
他们仍然会把更多事情下放给工程师
They'll still delegate more to eng,
但他们要对结果负主要责任
but they're squarely accountable.
这当然不是绝对泾渭分明的
It's not fully clean-cut.
还是要自己动脑子判断
It's like, use your head.
比如说如果这是一个一周的项目
Like if this is a one-week thing,
但争议非常大
but it's extremely controversial,
那PM可能还是应该亲自来主导
the PM should probably still drive it.
但我认为，这种做法会是越来越多公司开始采用的方式
But that, I think, is the approach that I expect more companies will start to do,
也就是授权工程师去当“小PM”
which is just deputize the engineers to be mini PMs.
当然，不是每个人都能做到这一点
Now, not everyone can do it, right?
所以那些更有产品思维的PM和工程师
So the PMs, the engineers who are more product-minded,
他们的价值会突然大幅提升
suddenly their value goes up significantly.
可以说是提升一个数量级
Like an order of magnitude.
而且我觉得我们可能还是会继续大量招聘PM
And then I think we will probably still be hiring a lot of PMs.
这里有太多有趣的点我想继续追问
There is so much interesting stuff I want to follow up on here.
好，先说第一个，就是“两周”这个概念
Okay, so one is this idea of two weeks.
简单说，我总是拿PM开玩笑说
Just briefly, I always joke as a PM,
你可以休个假，离开团队一两周，事情基本上
you can go on vacation and be away for like a couple weeks from your team and things are
也都还能运转得不错
going to be all right.
就是他们会，你懂的
Like they'll, you know,
团队有自己的惯性
there's like a momentum,
有既定计划，大家会继续推进
there's a plan, people keep operating.
而这听起来就有点像你们在用的这个经验法则
And it feels like that's kind of this rule of thumb you use of just,
就是说，如果是一个两周的项目
okay, if it's a two-week project,
没有PM也还能撑得住
you'll be all right without a PM.
你们可以搞定
You can handle it.
我很喜欢这两点能对应起来
I love that those two connect.
另外一点也非常有意思
Okay, the other here is so interesting.
你刚才的意思是，因为工程师的效率被大幅提升
So you're saying here that because engineers are so accelerated,
这一切都很合理
and this all makes sense,
结果就是PM和设计师会有点像是
PMs in design are kind of just like,
“天啊，完全跟不上工程这边的节奏”
holy shit, it's hard to keep up with the pace of engineering.
而你的意思是，为了跟上，就需要越来越多的PM
And what you're saying is you need more and more PMs to keep up.
这是一条路；另一条路基本上就是让工程师来做PM
That's one route. Or it's engineers that can PM, essentially.
这其实挺好笑的
Which is so funny.
就好像在说，好
It's just like, okay,
这对产品经理来说是个好消息
great news for product managers.
直到更多PM的工作可以由AI完成为止
Until more of the PM stuff can be done by AI.
但这是一个非常有意思的趋势
But that's a really interesting trend.
我在想，还有别的可以补充的吗
I don't know. Is there anything else there?
就是那种，“哇，我们其实可能需要更多PM”的感觉
Just like, oh, wow, we actually may need more PMs.
PM和工程师的比例提高，可能会是未来的趋势
The ratio of more PMs to your engineers might be the future.
是的，我觉得这其实
Yeah, I think this is like,
非常取决于所在行业
it just like really depends on the industry,
以及公司的规模
the size of company.
比如任何在做高度面向开发者产品的公司
Like any company where you're building something that's like much more developer-focused,
你就会更多地依赖工程师
like you're going to rely on the engineers a lot more.
在公司早期，你不会有那么多跨职能协调
Earlier companies, you don't have as much of this like cross-functional coordination,
也没有那么多需要PM去搞定的“对齐各方利益相关者”的繁文缛节
stakeholder alignment nonsense that you need all these PMs for.
所以你可以用更少的PM撑过去
So you can like get by with less.
但随着公司规模扩大
But then as a company scales and like,
如果我来想象一下
if I think about, okay,
现在在生产力上，原来1个PM可能相当于2个PM
now you have this ratio where maybe the 1PM became 2PMs from like productivity.
原来的5个工程师变成了20个工程师
That the like 5 engineers became like 20 engineers.
原来1个设计师可能变成了3个设计师
That one designer maybe became like three designers.
如果你去思考一下
If you think about like,
对那个PM来说，时间的最佳用法是什么
what is the best use of time for that PM?
我觉得这里有个非常有意思的问题
I think this is like a really interesting thing of like,
PM到底应该有多少时间亲自去交付功能，而不是做其他事情
how much should PMs be actually shipping things themselves versus everything else?
我认为在工程资源受限的世界里
I think like in the world where you're like limited on engineering,
PM确实应该亲自去交付一些东西
the PM should definitely be shipping things.
而在当今这个世界
I think in today's world,
这也是一个很好地理解这些工具的方式
it's a good way to like get an understanding of the tools,
而这点非常重要
which is really important.
所以出于这个原因，PM也应该亲自去交付
So the PM should be shipping for that reason.
但如果我是1到2个PM，却要面对20个工程师
But if I'm 1PM or 2PMs and there's 20 engineers,
我就会思考，我还能用时间创造多少增量价值
I think about what is the incremental value I can add with my time?
这个增量价值真的是来自于再去交付第21个PM做的功能吗
And is it actually shipping like the 21st PM feature?
还是来自于，我能不能更好地引导团队，找到真正正确的机会
Or is it saying, how am I getting a little bit better at guiding the team on what the right opportunities are?
所以在这样的世界里，我认为这是关键所在
And so that's where I think like in this world,
你可能会有一大堆工程师，他们就像一个个迷你产品经理
you may have all these engineers who are like mini PMs.
而且这种情况越明显越好
And the better that happens,
那就是我最想多花时间去做的事情所在
that's like where I would love to be doing more of.
但即便如此，如果你再招来一个非常优秀的产品经理，能把这一切进一步优化
But still, if you then get a really good PM who can come in and can like improve that,
不管是“为什么做”还是“要做什么”这两方面
the like why and the what,
哪怕只是提升个大约 5%
particularly by like 5%,
那都是一个杠杆极高的招聘
that is like such a high leverage hire.
你这个观点非常有意思
This is such an interesting insight you're making.
这几乎完全反着很多人对产品经理角色演变的看法
It's like so counter to how a lot of people are thinking PM is evolving.
我从你这儿听到的是：因为产品经理在节奏上严重落后
Like what I'm hearing here is because PMs are so behind,
因为工程师实在是完成了太多事情
because engineers are just getting so much done.
现在有很多人会说
There's like many people here,
好，你作为产品经理需要自己做原型
okay, you need to be prototyping,
你需要自己提 PR、自己上线
you need to be shipping PRs as a PM.
而你在说的——我也完全同意——是
What you're saying, which I completely agree with,
你的时间更应该花在帮助产品经理
is your time is much better spent helping PM,
以及本质上帮助工程师自己变成更好的“产品经理”
basically, and helping the engineers become better PMs themselves.
这种杠杆远远高于你自己花时间写代码
And the leverage there is a lot higher than you spending time coding,
在大多数情况下也远高于你自己去提 PR、上线
shipping PRs in most cases.
我觉得在某些情境下确实是这样
I think that's true in certain circumstances.
但如果是一个更小的公司
I think that as a smaller company,
我不确定情况还是不是这样
I don't know that that's the case.
在一个小公司里，大家都得上手干活
In a smaller company where it's all hands on deck,
你多半就得自己去上线、去交付
I think you probably need to be shipping.
如果你所在的公司预算非常紧
I think if you're in a company where budgets are very tight,
工程师人手也非常紧张
and engineers are very tight,
而且你不能因为钱多就随便招人
and you're not able to just hire because money is unlimited,
那你就得做一切必要的事来加速团队能产生的影响
then you need to do what is needed to accelerate the impact your team's going to have.
所以在不少情况下，作为产品经理
So there's going to be a number of cases where as a PM,
正确的做法就是
the right thing to do is to be like,
管他的，我自己来做，我从头到尾全包了
screw it, I am shipping and I am going it the whole way.
但我刚才说的更多是针对更大的公司、已经规模化的业务
But I'm talking here more about the larger companies, more scaled businesses.
是啊，如果你有 20 个工程师
Yeah, if you have 20 engineers,
你时间的最高杠杆用法真的是再多上线一个功能吗
is it the highest leverage of your time to ship an extra feature,
还是去思考如何整体提升我们在做的一切
or figure out how do I up-level everything that we're doing,
比如更好地获取用户洞察之类的
get the user insights better, etc?
对，而且我觉得还有一种“为了学习而上线”的成分
Yeah, and I think there's also an element of shipping to learn,
通过做一个原型，让你能形成更成熟的判断
building a prototype so that you can have a better opinion.
很多人会说，先随便试三件事
Like a lot of people talk about just going to try three things,
看看效果如何，再用这些结果来反哺路线图
see how it goes, and that'll help inform the roadmap.
这就成了新的 PRD：别再空谈，直接看这个东西本身
This is now the PRD, is look at it instead of talking about it.
所以这里面依然有很多价值
So there's a lot of value there still.
这非常对，我觉得这是个很好的观点
That's very true. I think that's a great point.
所以就算对我现在来说，我们已经有不少产品经理
So even for me now, where we've got a number of PMs,
也有很多工程师
we've got many engineers,
有些时候我还是会想
there are certain times when I'm like,
我想把脑子里的想法表达清楚
I want to articulate the idea I have in my head.
那我自己做个原型拿出来给大家看会更好，对吧
It's just better for me to prototype it and show it, right?
所以我觉得这一点真的很重要
So I think that is really important.
另外我们内部风格非常“能凑就凑”、极度务实
And then we are very scrappy.
名义上我们是一家大公司
So we're a big company by name,
估值也很高，但我们做事极其草根、节俭
valuation, but we're extremely scrappy.
内部的重点就是尽量减少官僚流程，然后直接干
And the focus internally is just minimize bureaucracy and just go.
所以大概有 70%，也许 60
And so probably 70%, maybe 60,
70、80% 的上线内容是没有 PRD 的
70, 80% of what we ship does not have a PRD.
我个人是很排斥 PRD 的
I am averse to PRDs.
我就是讨厌写文档
I just hate documentation.
我就只想说：干干干
I'm just like, go, go, go.
把一切阻碍都砍掉
Just cut the blockers.
有 20、30% 的事情是比较重要的
20, 30% of stuff where it's important.
这些事情必须要做对
It's really important to get right.
这类事情的文档就应该写得非常好，大家也应该在上面花很多时间
Like the documentation should be really good and that people should spend a lot of time on it.
但总体来说，我觉得 PRD 这种东西在现在已经有点过时了
But by and large, I think PRDs are just outdated at this point.
有一个好的团队，你完全可以不用这些东西就把项目启动起来
And you can just kick things off with a good team without needing to do that sort of thing.
多说说这个
Say more about that.
你会怎么做来确保这一点
What do you do to help make sure?
因为大家现在可以构建得非常快，也可能在错误方向上花掉大量时间
Because people can build so fast or spend a lot of time going in the wrong direction,
最后交付的东西还不是你真正想要的
ship things that are not what you're asking.
那你是怎么启动一个项目并且讲清楚
How do you kick off a project and clarify,
“我们到底要做什么”的
here's what we're doing?
只是靠一场对话，还是还有别的东西
Is it just a conversation or is there anything beyond that?
这其实非常取决于项目的规模
It really depends on the size of it.
这又回到了我们说的那个“两周”的标准
And this kind of goes back to like the two week thing.
我们为什么要设定那个两周的标准
Why do we have that two week thing?
更像是说，我们怎么设一个筛子
It's more like, how do we have some filter to say,
如果我们要在某件事上投入很多
if we're investing heavily into something,
那我们就应该在背后多花点脑子
we should apply more thinking behind it.
相反，如果只是一些小投入
Versus if it's a smaller set of investments,
那就直接干就行
just go for it.
而作为一个增长团队
And as a growth team,
你确实会有相当多这种小事情要做
again, you do have a decent amount of these smaller things that you do.
所以对于非常小的改动
So for very small changes,
你可能会说，哦，有个东西要上线了
you're like, oh, there's a thing coming.
我们需要给它做一个向上销售的入口
We need to have an upsell for it.
那我们到底要做什么呢
What is the thing we're doing?
这种事就在 Slack 上说一说就行，对吧
Like, this is just on Slack, right?
完全就是在 Slack 上沟通
This is just purely on Slack.
就是几条消息来回聊一聊
It's just a messages back and forth.
而且我觉得这也取决于你有没有一批素质很高的工程师
And I think it also depends on having a good caliber of engineer in there,
这些工程师能理解
but engineers can understand like,
“好，我知道你是这么说的
hey, I know you said this,
但从用户的角度看，那样做会怎么样呢”
but what about that for the audience?
所以在这点上我们很幸运，有很多有产品思维的工程师
And so we're lucky we have good product minded engineers in that sense.
但所有这些小事基本上就是在 Slack 上来回聊几句就搞定
But all these smaller things are very much just on Slack back and forth.
你就是这么干的
And that's what you do.
对于更大的项目
For the larger things,
我非常坚信要有一次正式的项目启动会
I think I very firmly believe in a proper kickoff.
因为我们这里事情实在太多了
So we still do just this so much going on at this place.
大家都没时间
No one's got time.
也没人能完全搞清楚到底发生了什么
No one knows what's going on.
所以要做一次跨职能的启动会
And so doing a cross-functional kickoff,
把法务拉进来，把安全合规拉进来
get legal, get safeguards,
把所有人都叫到一个屋里，然后直接说
get everyone in the room and just be like,
这是我们打算要做的事情
this is what we plan to do.
你在意什么
What do you care about?
对于比较大的项目，那种 30 分钟的会议就是
Like that 30 minute meeting for larger things is just,
我觉得依然非常重要，可以理顺如果你不提前做这些工作之后可能出现的各种混乱
I think, still so important to just streamline all the mess that may happen later if you
如果你一开始不做这些工作的话
don't do that work early on.
在这种情况下，你是怎么写那个 PRD 的
What's your approach to crafting that PRD in those cases?
是那种对着 Claude 一通乱说吗
Is it like ramble into Claude?
还是你有一个模板
Do you have a template?
即便在这些情况下，有时候我也不会写 PRD
Even in those cases, there are times I don't craft the PRD.
因为一切进展得太快了对吧
Because everything's moving so quickly, right?
所以有些时候我只是把会约好 然后在会前大概五
So there's still some of those cases where I just set up the meeting and then like five
分钟把内容丢进 Cowork 里
minutes before I'll put it into Cowork.
比如说 我的一些想法
Like, you know, some of my thoughts,
要归功于谁之类的 以及这些是我需要考虑的点
what credit, like here are the things that I need to think about.
起一个很基础的文档 然后拿它来对着讨论
Spin up like a basic doc and we use it to talk.
还有的时候我甚至连文档都不会准备
Other times I won't even have a doc.
但如果我要写 PRD 的话
But if I am creating a PRD,
我基本上有一个自己做好的技能
I have basically a skill that I've created.
里面有一个项目集合 放着之前所有的 PRD
And then there's projects with all the previous PRDs in there.
然后我会用它 其实很简单
And then I will... it's pretty simple.
它已经把格式都固定好了
Like, it has the format down.
所以我只要写上 这些是我在意的点
So I'll just say here are the things I care about.
这是原因 这是问题
Here's the why. Here's the problem.
然后把关键考量点展开写清楚
And flesh out the key considerations,
把跨职能相关方也写清楚
flesh out the cross-functional stakeholders,
类似这样的内容
those types of things.
但再说一遍 我的默认是 如果能不写文档 直接进入行动
But again, my default is like if I can avoid the doc and if we can just jump to action,
那我们就应该这么做
then that's what we should do.
而且越来越多的时候是直接跳到做原型
And increasingly just jump to prototyping the thing.
是的 而一旦我们能把更多这些东西自动化 我觉得就会变得非常有趣
Yeah, and that's where I think it'll get so interesting once we can automate more of that.
就像你的助手去跟法务的助手对话
Just like your assistant talking to the legal assistant,
把所有这些细枝末节都捋顺
just like ironing out all these little,
比如说 对你来说什么重要
you know, what's important to you,
对某某来说什么重要
what's important to the...
对 而且这马上就要实现了
Yes, and it's coming.
而且我觉得法务团队在这方面做了很好的赋能
And I think the legal team has done like good enablement around this.
比如我们会在不同版本里探索 你要怎么
Like we work in versions of like how do you...
你可以想想 怎么去模拟某个人可能会说的话 然后搭建起
you can think about like how can you mimic what someone might say and like set up,
比如说 一个法庭那样的场景对吧
you know, like a court, right?
所以类似这样的东西
So there's things like that,
我觉得我们现在已经有了
that I think that we have now.
然后随着 Claude 能拿到越来越多上下文 并且更擅长传递长上下文
And then as Claude gets more and more context and gets better at passing long context,
我觉得这些都是 Claude 会越来越擅长掌握的事情
I think these are things that Claude will just get better at knowing.
其中一件事啊，Lenny，这有点算是跑题
One of the things, Lenny, it's like a slight tangent,
但我觉得其中一个
but one of the, I think,
我用 Claude 最有效 或者说最有趣的方式之一是
most effective ways I use Claude or one of the most interesting ways I use Claude is,
我看到很多内部同事也在这么用 就是帮你识别不一致的地方
which I see a number of people doing internally is to like help you identify misalignment.
这点我觉得
This is like, I think,
对我非常非常有帮助
something that I found really, really helpful.
So with Cowork, you have the Slack MCP and you can tell Cowork to say,
在 Cowork 里 你有 Slack MCP 你可以让 Cowork 去
基本上是通览整个 Slack
basically, look across Slack,
你知道我在做哪些项目
you know the projects that I'm working on.
这些是我现在最关心的事情
These are the things that are top of mind.
去帮我找出目前可能存在不一致的地方
Go and find me areas of potential misalignment right now.
而且它做得非常非常好
And it does a really, really good job.
所以这是我每周都会定时跑的一件事
So this is something that I have scheduled runs every week.
Claude 会去看这些东西 然后回来跟我说
Claude's like looking at things and coming back to me and saying like,
我觉得这些点你需要注意
I think these things you should be aware of.
所以放到发布产品的场景里你也可以这么想
And so you can think about in that shipping context,
类似地 Claude 基本上可以去看整个
it's a similar thing where Claude can basically be looking at what's happening across the
公司里正在发生什么 然后说 你正打算发布这个东西
company and say, you're thinking about shipping this thing.
这些是你需要去沟通的人
Here's who you need to talk to.
这些是你需要记住的点
Here's what you need to keep in mind.
这也太酷了
That is so cool.
我非常兴奋地想跟你介绍本季的支持赞助商 Vanta
I am so excited to tell you about this season's supporting sponsor, Vanta.
Vanta helps over 15,000 companies like Cursor, Ramp, Duolingo, Snowflake,
Vanta 帮助了超过 15,000 家公司 比如 Cursor Ramp Duolingo Snowflake
以及 Atlassian 在客户面前建立并证明信任
and Atlassian earn and prove trust with their customers.
多亏了 AI 各个团队构建和发布产品的速度前所未有地快
Teams are building and shipping products faster than ever thanks to AI.
但相应地 被引入你的产品和业务中的风险量
But as a result, the amount of risk being introduced into your product and your business
也达到了前所未有的高度
is higher than it's ever been.
我和每一位安全负责人聊天时 他们都在感受到保护自己组织和业务的压力不断增加
Every security leader that I talk to is feeling the increasing weight of protecting their organization, their business,
更不用说还要保护客户数据
and not to mention their customer data.
因为一切变化太快
Because things are moving so fast,
他们总是在被动应对
they are constantly reacting,
只能去猜什么是优先级最高的
having to guess at priorities,
还不得不将就使用过时的解决方案
and having to make do with outdated solutions.
Vanta 通过 35 个以上的安全和隐私
Vanta automates compliance and risk management with over 35 security and privacy
frameworks, including SOC 2, ISO 27001, and HIPAA.
各种框架，包括 SOC 2、ISO 27001 和 HIPAA
这能帮助公司快速达成合规并持续保持合规状态
This helps companies get compliant fast and stay compliant.
比以往任何时候都更明显的是
More than ever before,
信任足以成就或毁掉你的业务
trust has the power to make or break your business.
了解更多信息 请访问 vanta.com 斜杠 lenny
Learn more at vanta.com slash lenny.
作为本播客的听众
And as a listener of this podcast,
你可以在购买 Vanta 时减免 1000 美元
you get $1,000 off Vanta.
That's vanta.com slash lenny.
地址是 vanta.com 斜杠 lenny
我感觉这里有一条
I feel like there's this like,
产品经理的工作到底是什么
what are the jobs of a product manager?
然后这些工作会如何逐步被 AI 支持或直接完成
And then how are they slowly going to be supported slash done by AI?
所以有一块是关于不一致
So there's this misalignment,
就是去发现不一致
just like fine misalignment.
然后也许有一天会变成 一开始就帮大家对齐
And then maybe one day it'll be like align people initially.
你之前提到过用于增长的 CASH 自动化
You talked about this cash automation for growing.
比如说 我要怎么让这个产品实现增长
Like, how do I grow this product?
这种事情已经开始发生了
That's starting to happen.
还有一个是我自己在做东西时会用的方式，就是直接问
Another that I might use myself when I'm building stuff is just asking,
我该如何让这个产品变得更好
how do I make this product better?
我该如何让这个用户体验变得更好
How do I make this a better user experience?
然后让 AI 给我一堆点子，而且这些点子其实都挺不错
And asking the AI just give me a bunch of ideas and they're actually really good.
所以很有意思的是，这些小模块正开始被拼接起来，去承担更多
So it's interesting how these little pieces are starting to be put into place to do more
越来越多原本由这个角色完成的工作
and more of this role.
我很好奇你和你的团队还有哪些行之有效的自动化
I'm curious what other automations you have and your team have that are effective.
我喜欢这些对话的一点是，你基本上已经生活在未来了
What I love about these conversations is you're basically living in the future.
你在一家最前沿的公司工作，身边是最有才华的人，使用
You're working in like the most bleeding edge company with the most talented people with
最尖端的工具
the most cutting edge tools.
你能看到事情的发展方向，并开始真正活在未来
And you can like see where things are going and start to actually live in the future,
去构建别人还没想到、也做不到的东西
build things that nobody else has even thought about or can do.
我就很好奇还有哪些东西是有效的
I'm curious just what else is working,
你们团队还做了什么来帮你节省时间、提升效率
what else your team has done to help save you time, be more productive.
我们在各个方面都用得非常广泛
We use it pretty extensively across the board, right?
比如有一些标准的产品经理工作，像写文档
So there's a standard PM stuff like writing docs,
头脑风暴、看数据
brainstorming, looking at data.
在数据方面，我个人有一个 Cowork 代理按计划运行，每天查看大概二十
For data, I personally have like a co-worker runs on a schedule and looks at sort of 20,
二十五个不同的图表
25 different charts every morning.
所以当我早上进办公室时
And then so when I come in the morning,
有太多图表
there's just so many charts,
太多产品需要跟踪
so many products to track.
Cowork 会告诉我，好，这些就是你需要注意的事情
Cowork will tell me, OK, here are the things that you should pay attention to.
这里是一些值得担心的点，还有一些有意思的洞见
Here's like what is concerning and here are just some like interesting insights.
那它是通过 Slack 给你发更新，还是大概是什么工作流
And it sends you the update in Slack or what's kind of the workflow?
对我来说，它就直接在 Cowork 里弹出来
For me, it just shows it comes up in Cowork.
Cowork 里有一个日程调度
So Cowork has a schedule.
在桌面应用里
In the desktop app.
对，在桌面应用里
Yeah, in the desktop app,
你可以创建一个定时任务
you can have a scheduled task that you create.
所以我有一堆 Hex 的链接，它会自动去查看
And so I have a bunch of hex links that it will go and look at.
有些事情它用 Chrome 插件，有些事情用 MCP
It uses the Chrome extension for some things and uses MCP for other things.
然后它会给我一个总结
And then it'll just give me a summary.
然后我会自己再看几张我喜欢看的图表，因为我就是
And then I know like I saw this a few charts that I just like to look at because I just
这么一个人
like, I mean, I'm this guy.
我就是喜欢图表
I just like charts.
我也会把它们放在右边
I'll put to the right too.
我喜欢亲自看图表
So I like to see the chart.
但除此之外，还有一大堆长尾的东西
But then there's like a long tail of things.
甚至还有一堆中尾的东西
And even the medium tail where it's like,
你根本没时间每天都看
you don't have time to look at it every day.
如果 Claude 能主动去看这些东西，随着时间推移你会开始觉得放心
That if Claude is proactively looking at it and you start to feel good over time of,
比如，好，误报率在下降
okay, it's like the false positive rate is going down.
Claude 提醒给你的东西里，漏报率也在下降
The like false negative rate is going down of the things that Claude brings to you.
那你在这方面的信心和安心感就会更强一点
Then you just get a little bit more confidence and peace of mind there.
这就触及到我一直有的一个想法：团队会拥有一个战略机器人
This touches on an idea I've always had that teams will have is a strategy bot.
想象一个代理，它持续地监控各项指标
Which just imagine an agent that's just constantly watching metrics,
市场、产品路线图
the market, the roadmap,
哪些有效、哪些无效
what's working, what's not.
然后它会说，Hamel
And just like, Hamel,
这是我觉得我们现在该做的事
here's what I think we should do now.
这是我们应该做的转向
Here's the pivot we should take.
这是我们会赢的地方
Here's where we're going to win.
感觉我们离这个已经非常近了
Like, it feels like we're very close to that.
我觉得我们已经很接近了
I think we're close.
我觉得我们会在今年晚些时候达到那种非常非常有效的程度
I think we'll get there later this year to like the point where that's very, very effective.
这是我的直觉，我认为那种主动性，以及跨大量上下文去观察并提炼洞见的能力
That's my gut. I think that level of like proactivity and getting looking across a bunch of context and distilling insights.
我觉得这有点像我之前提到的那个东西
I think it's like the thing I mentioned earlier,
Lenny，就是关于对齐那一块
Lenny, about the alignment piece.
现在已经有了一个类似的版本
That's like a version of it right now.
只是你会跨更多数据源去看
You're just looking at across more data sources.
这是我自己在用的东西
This is something that I use.
我刚才说了一些标准的产品经理工作，头脑风暴、数据、用户研究
So I talked about some of the standard PM stuff, brainstorming, data, UXR.
还有很多行政杂事
There's a lot of admin stuff.
我就是讨厌生活行政和各种文书工作
I just hate life admin and paperwork.
我真的很讨厌
I just hate it.
所以我让 Claude 帮我预订会议室
And so I get Claude to book my meeting rooms.
我自己不订会议室
I don't book meeting rooms.
Claude 会先帮我归档邮件，做第一轮清理收件箱
Claude archives my email first pass at clearing out my inbox.
我不自己报销、也不自己处理费用
I don't do any of my reimbursements and expenses.
Claude will go to Benepass and file the reimbursements.
Claude 会去 Benepass 上提交报销
它会去 Brex 上提交费用
He'll go to Brex and file the expenses.
所以这一整块事情
So all of that side of things,
我就直接交给 Cowork
I'm just like, just hand it to Cowork.
让它统统搞定
Just get rid of it.
然后还有一些挺有意思的东西
And then the stuff that's quite interesting,
我觉得是管理者视角，我之前说的对齐是一方面
I think, is like the manager lens where I talked about alignment is one thing.
我也会纵览我所有的直属下属
I look also across my direct reports.
Claude 可以查看他们这周都做了什么
Claude can look into what have they done this week.
它会看我们的团队目标和 OKR
You look at sort of our team goals and OKRs,
看我们讨论的文字记录并进行理解
look at the transcripts from our discussions and understand.
我基本上可以问 Claude
I can basically ask Claude,
我应该记住的关键要点和观察是什么
what are the key takeaways and observations I should keep in mind?
以及你觉得我应该给他们什么反馈
And what feedback do you think I should give them?
这件事其实是可以
And that's something that is like,
同样，你可以设成每周自动运行
again, you can just set that up weekly.
现在质量有点忽好忽坏
The quality is like hit or miss right now.
有些时候还挺不错
It's like it's decent on something.
有时候你会觉得，天哪，我真庆幸我发现了这个
Sometimes you're like, holy shit, like I am so glad that I caught this.
这就非常有帮助
And that's very, very helpful.
然后我也会对自己用同样的方法
And then I do that for myself as well.
所以我基本上是这样
So I basically...
我的经理 Ami Vora 好像曾经上过你的播客节目，对吧
My manager, Ami Vora was, I think, a podcast guest of yours, right?
所以我会说，嘿，基于你对 Ami 的了解
So I say, hey, based on what you know of Ami,
包括公开的信息，她写过大量关于产品的内容，还有内部的信息以及我们之间的讨论
both publicly, she's written extensively about product and then internally and then our discussions.
基于我这周做了或没做的所有事情
What is, based on everything that I've done or not done this week,
你以 Ami 的视角，会给我什么反馈
what feedback do you have for me as Ami?
而且我每周都会得到这些对吧
And I get that every week, right?
所以很多这样的事情其实今天已经可以做到
So a lot of these things can already be done today.
我认为随着模型不断提升
I think that as the models improve,
我觉得就是这些东西的准确性和信号质量会持续快速提升
I think it's just like the accuracy and the signal of these things is going to continue to improve rapidly.
我觉得你还没意识到你在这里分享的东西有多厉害
I don't think you realize just how much awesomeness you're sharing here.
基本上你说的每一条都让我有种“哇靠”的感觉
This is just like every one of these is like, what?
好的 那我们说说这个 Ami 的例子
OK, so this Ami example.
你会和她做一对一沟通
So you have one-on-ones with her.
你会问 比如你会让 Claude Cowork 把她写过的所有东西都过一遍
You ask, so do you ask Claude Cowork to go through all of her writing,
基本上相当于先构建一个关于她的模型 然后你再问
basically build like a model of her and you ask,
基于你对 Ami 的了解 我应该在哪些方面做得不一样
what should I be doing differently based on what you know about Ami?
你的做法是这样的吗
Is that the approach?
对 差不多是这样 当然有很多种具体做法
Yeah, effectively, there's a number of ways you can do this.
我觉得如果某个人有公开主页 而且写了很多东西
I think if someone has a public profile where they've written extensively,
这就很有帮助 因为 Claude 可以直接获取所有这些信息
it's helpful because Claude can just get all that information.
否则 你也可以围绕一个项目或者一项技能来做
Otherwise, you can have a project or you can have a skill.
但现在 Claude 在直接理解方面越来越强 因为你可以对 Claude 说
But increasingly, Claude is better at just understanding because you can tell Claude,
like look on Cowork, you can say using the Slack MCP,
比如在 Cowork 上 你可以说 用 Slack MCP
看看这个人在过去一周里说过的所有话之类的
look at everything that this person has said in the last week, etc.
然后基于这些内容
And based on that, like,
他们最重要的优先事项是什么
what are their top priorities?
从他们实际花时间的方式来看 我的经理有哪些我不知道的优先事项
What are priorities my manager has based on how they're spending the time that I don't know?
所以这一整层东西
And so all of this layer of stuff,
我会把它看作是一种软性教练
which is like that, I think about it as like soft coaching.
我觉得这一块其实已经被解锁了
I think that that is like unlocked,
至少在我看来已经可以做到
in my opinion, already.
只是现在有点像你在和一个教练合作 但这个教练有点
I think it's just that you're like working with a coach who's like,
有时候像是喝醉了一样
kind of like drunk at times,
也不是说真醉了 但你懂我的意思
not drunk, but like, you know,
有时候它会说一句话 你会想 为什么
like sometimes like says something, you're like, why?
你为什么会提这个
Like, why would you bring that up?
这明显是不对的
Like, that's clearly wrong.
但在另外一些时候你会觉得
But other times you're like,
哇 这太有用了 我们有个同事
wow, like, that has, there's like one of the guys,
Scott 他负责我们的企业团队
Scott, who leads our enterprise team,
我记得有几次是这样的
I think he, there's a few cases where it's like,
他发现了一些重大的不对齐 如果没发现 团队本来会在这些地方空转
he found major areas of misalignment that would have caused teams to sort of spin their
浪费大量时间 或者做大量重复工作
wheels significantly or do overlapping work.
你想想这一点
And you think about that,
这种影响有多大 在当今这个世界 对一家更大的公司来说 你的交付往往会被
the impact of that, like your shipping in this world is a bigger company is going to be
各种跨职能协作严重掣肘 对吧
constrained at often by all the cross-functional coordination, right?
而我觉得我们现在开始在这个跨职能协作层面看到
And I think we're now starting to see at this cross-functional coordination layer,
有一部分工作 AI 已经真的可以用来减少这些繁琐劳动
some of that work, AI is really being able to be used to reduce that toil.
而在六个月前 我觉得这还做不到
And I think that six months ago, that wasn't possible.
所以我现在会想 天哪 再过六个月
And I'm like, shit, like six months from now,
在这方面又能做到什么程度
what is going to be possible there?
是啊 而且关键在于现在这些数据都在那儿 Slack 也好 Granola 也好
Oh, man. And I think the fact that all this data is there, Slack, there's Granola,
不管大家用什么工具 这些对话和讨论的笔记
whatever people use, like all these notes from conversations and discussions are really
都是让这一切能运转起来的关键
key to this working.
对 那如果有人也想做类似的事情
Yes. So for someone that wants to do something like this,
该怎么搭这个东西
what, how do you set this up?
大概有哪些步骤
What's kind of the steps?
嗯 你去 Cowork 上 在 Cowork 上下载桌面应用
Yeah, you go on to Cowork, download the desktop app on Cowork,
然后把 Slack MCP 连上去
connect the Slack MCP.
这一步你就需要
That's where you need to,
视你们组织规模而定
depending on how big the organization is,
可能需要拿到团队或企业级管理员权限
you may need to get sort of team or enterprise admin permissions to,
让有这些权限的人帮你开通
you know, someone with those permissions to enable that.
But once you have the Slack MCP connected and on Cowork,
但一旦你把 Slack MCP 接到 Cowork 上
接下来你只要问 Claude 就行
you just ask Claude.
就这样 太厉害了 好
That's it. Amazing. Okay.
我想换个方向聊聊
I want to go in a kind of a different direction.
我想谈谈 Anthropic 这些年来的专注
I want to talk about the focus that Anthropic has had over the years.
如果你看看你们现在交出的这些数字
So if you look at the numbers that you're all putting up,
真正令人惊讶的是你们保持的这种专注
what's really incredible about it is the focus that you all have had.
而我觉得这就是你们能做得这么好的原因
And I think this is the reason that has worked out so well.
市场上有家竞争对手已经开始意识到他们本该这么做
There's a certain competitor in the market that is realizing they should have done this
现在也开始往类似的路线转
and are starting to shift to a similar approach.
作为一个外部观察者
As an external observer,
在我看来 Anthropic 很擅长只做很少几件事
it feels like Anthropic has been very good at doing very few things,
但在这些事上挖得非常深
but going super deep.
比如 B2B 你们就死磕 B2B 然后在编码类用例上也挖得特别深
So B2B, for example, just going deep on B2B and then going really deep on coding use
cases, Claude Code being an example.
Claude Code 就是一个例子
而且事实证明效果非常好
And it's worked out really well.
是谁在推动这种专注
Who's been driving that focus?
从一开始是谁在帮助维持这种专注
Who has helped keep that focus from the beginning?
我觉得这是公司最基础的一部分
Yeah, I mean, I think it's a foundational part of the company.
从最早期开始就一直存在
I think it's been there from the very, very early days.
而且这确实是来自领导层
And it really comes from leadership.
我觉得他们在把这种理念提炼出来方面做得非常出色
And I think they've just done a phenomenal job of distilling that.
我最近看到一份文档又被翻出来
I saw this doc come up recently.
我也不太记得是在哪儿分享的
I don't know where it was shared.
是 Ben Mann 写的一个东西
It was something that Ben Mann,
他是我们在播客里提到的那位创始人之一
one of our founders on the podcast, had written.
文档日期是 2021 年 大概是他们创办公司几个月之后
It's dated in 2021, I think a few months after they started the company.
文档的核心就是 我们为什么应该只专注在 AI 编码上
And it was like, here's why we should just focus on AI coding.
这还是大概五年前的事
And this is like five years ago.
那时候还远远没人搞清楚这里真正的市场机会是什么
This is long before anyone knew what the actual market opportunities were around this.
而我觉得这就是我们从一开始在内部就有的那种深度专注
And I think this is just like a deep focus that we have had internally from the start on
专注在编码和 B2B 的重要性上
the importance of coding and B2B.
我觉得可以从两个视角来看
I think there's like two lenses to it.
一个是这样的看法
It's like maybe a view of,
好 这是一个在商业上值得去做的方向
okay, this is going to be commercially beneficial to tackle.
另一个则是它能加速研究
And then also the side of it around accelerating research.
现在我会说 这已经是一个相当主流的观点了
So I'd say it's a pretty mainstream view now.
我已经听到很多不同实验室的人在谈这件事
I've now heard people from various labs talking about this,
就是编码对加速研究的重要性
the importance of coding to accelerate research.
但这一直是我们在内部高度聚焦的一条非常坚定的观点
But that has just been like a very firm view that we have been laser focused on internally
就是说 如果你拥有最好的模型
of, okay, if you have the best models,
那会加速你的研究进程 也会加速整个研究循环
that's going to accelerate your research and that's going to accelerate the research loop.
我觉得这是 Dario 在过去好几年里一直看得非常清楚的一件事
I think that's something that like Dario has seen very clearly for a number of years.
所以我会说 这可能只是众多因素之一
So I would say that that's probably one of a lot.
我认为很多东西都来自 Dario
I think a lot comes from Dario.
我觉得很大一部分来自领导层 以及我们公司的基因
I think a lot comes from leadership and just our DNA.
但我觉得第二点
I think the second, though,
可能就是出于一种必要性
is probably just like necessity.
就是说 如果你
Where if you're, you know,
现在情况变了 公司更知名了
it's now changed with a more well-known company,
融了很多钱 诸如此类
raise lots of money, blah, blah, blah.
但从历史上看 我们一直都是那种最小的玩家
But historically, we were very much like the smallest,
在这个领域里资金最少的那一方
least well-funded player in this space.
在很多方面 我觉得我们能走到今天这一步简直是个奇迹
In many ways, it's a complete miracle that I think we've gotten to the stage that we have.
我们没有像 Meta 或 Google 那样的自由现金流或分发能力
We didn't have the free cash flow or the distribution of a meta or Google.
我们也没有 OpenAI 那样的先发优势
We didn't have the first mover advantage of an open AI.
那你还能怎么办呢
And so what do you do, right?
我自己在人生中有一个更广泛的原则 就是通过约束获得自由
I think there's this broader principle I have just around life of the freedom through
当你身上被施加了很多约束时
constraints that when you have a bunch of constraints applied on you,
不管是在个人生活中还是在工作中
whether that's in personal life or at work.
我认为那反而能带来很多自由 因为它帮你剔除了那些多余的选择
I think that can bring a lot of freedom because it just frees up all this excess choice.
你会觉得 好 这条路显然就是要走的路
You're like, OK, this is clearly the path.
对我们来说也是这样
And I think for us, it's like,
好 你没有很多资金
OK, you don't have a ton of funding.
你是个小玩家
You're a small player.
你没有分发能力
You don't have distribution.
你就必须选一个非常狭窄的聚焦点
You just have to really pick a very narrow focus.
即便这是一项高度通用的技术 也要这样做 才能最大化你达到逃逸速度的机会
And even for a very generalizable technology to maximize your chances of getting to escape velocity.
我觉得这也和历史的走向有关 对吧
And I think that that's also just related to how history played out, right?
那都是在我加入之前很久发生的
So it was well before my time.
但当时 Anthropic 已经有了一个版本的 Claude
But Anthropic had a version of Claude.
在 ChatGPT 发布之前 我们就已经有一个聊天机器人了
We had a chatbot before ChatGPT was launched.
但最终我们出于安全原因选择不发布
And we had ultimately chosen not to launch it for safety reasons.
我觉得团队不想等于是在引爆一场全球性的 AI 军备竞赛
I think the team didn't want to kick off effectively an AI global arms race.
然后 ChatGPT 发布了 他们获得了疯狂的用户和关注 对吧
And ChatGPT launched and they got insane traction, right?
这自然就把他们拉向了消费级市场
And that just naturally sort of pulled them towards consumer.
也可以想象另一种世界 如果当初是 Anthropic 先发布 Claude
There's another world where if Anthropic had launched Claude first,
也许一切就会反过来
maybe the other way around,
即便有我们刚才说的那些聚焦策略
even with all that focus stuff.
所以谁知道呢 回头看这些事总是很难下定论
So who knows? It's always hard to say looking back at some of these things.
哇 我之前完全不知道这件事
Wow, I didn't know that.
我觉得大家也没意识到 Anthropic 以前到底有多落后
I think also people just don't realize how far behind Anthropic was.
现在大家会觉得
Like right now, it's like,
他们当然很厉害
of course, they're amazing.
但我记得当时大家在谈 Anthropic 的时候
But I just remember when people were talking about Anthropic,
我们正在融资
we were raising money.
我当时心想 以他们那会儿的状况 根本不可能和 OpenAI 竞争
I was like, there's no way they're going to compete with OpenAI at this point.
感觉局势已经尘埃落定 对方领先太多了
It's like so over, just like they're so far ahead.
而这恰好说明了聚焦的力量
And it shows the power of focus.
还有就是 我想 也许是
And just, I guess, I don't know,
你们做的所有那些事情
all the things y'all did.
你们能走到今天这一步 有这么大的成功 而且一切变化得这么快 真是不可思议
Like, it is absurd how far y'all have come and how successful and how things have changed so quickly.
是的 而且我非常同意
Yeah. And I would say I very much agree.
我认为这很大程度上要归功于我们的领导团队
I think a lot of that comes down to our leadership team.
我们有不少人曾在你所知道的全球顶级公司工作过
We have a number of people who've worked at the best companies you know in the world.
都是非常资深的人 而且几乎所有人都一致认为
Very senior people. And I think almost uniformly,
大家都觉得 这是他们见过最强的领导团队
everyone's like, this is the strongest leadership team.
比他们待过的任何一家公司都强
Out of any of those companies.
所以我觉得很多优势都来自他们
And so I think a lot comes from them.
另外我们也很幸运 拥有一群非常出色的同事
And then we're just very lucky to have incredible people.
我觉得这也起了很大的作用
I think that helps a lot as well.
关于编码这一块 我想再澄清一下
On the coding piece, just to make sure that part is clear.
我之前从没这样想过
I never thought about this,
你们之所以在编码上押注这么深 不只是因为那是一个巨大的可服务市场
that the reason that the bet was so deep on coding is not just that's a huge TAM,
而是因为这会形成一个不断加速我们的反馈循环
but it's that this is a feedback loop that will accelerate us further and further.
所以如果我们在编码上做到最好
So if we get the best at coding,
编码就会帮助我们做研究 帮助我们构建更好的模型 让我们加速得越来越快
coding will help us do research and help us build better models and accelerate faster and faster.
对 没错 这点我也确认过
Yeah, that's correct. And this is something I checked,
Dario 公开谈过这件事
Dario has talked about this publicly,
所以我也可以公开说
so I'm fine too.
这样一说就很有道理
Like, okay, it makes sense.
安全这一块真的很有意思
The safety piece is really interesting.
所以我想在这里多花一点时间
So I want to spend a little time here.
So famously, Anthropic, I think the official name of Anthropic is Anthropic and AI Safety Research Company.
众所周知 Anthropic 的正式名称好像是 Anthropic an AI Safety Research Company
作为一个做增长的人 我想你需要在增长和
As a growth person, there's this balance I imagine you strike between growing and just and
公司使命之间做平衡 使命并不是不惜一切代价去增长
the mission being don't grow at all costs.
我们的目标是 AI 安全和对齐
Our goal is AI safety and alignment.
你是如何平衡这两者的
How do you balance those two things?
这对你的工作有什么影响
How does that impact your job?
我觉得这是我们极其严肃对待的一件事
Look, I think it's something we take very, very seriously.
也是这家公司存在的根本原因
And it is the whole reason the company exists.
如果你仔细想想
And if you think about it,
这从一开始就贯穿始终
it's all the way from...
这是他们离开原公司创业的原因
it's why they left to start the company.
也深深写进了我们的公司治理结构
It's deep in our corporate structure itself.
过去 大家在融资时通常会
So historically, everyone raising money is like,
去注册一家特拉华州 C 类公司
go create a Delaware C Corp.
那就是标准结构
And that's the structure you do.
而在这种公司架构下
And with a corporation,
你在法律上有受托责任 要最大化股东回报 最大化股东价值
you have a fiduciary duty to maximize returns for shareholders, maximize shareholder value.
但从一开始
And from the beginning,
他们就选择了一条不同的路
they went a different way.
我们选择设立的是一家公益公司
We went to create a public benefit corporation,
也就是 PBC 这种结构在法律上允许你声明 最大化股东价值并不是
PBC, which allows you to legally say that maximizing shareholder value is not the
这家公司的最高总目标
overarching umbrella goal of this company.
你可以优先优化公共利益
And you can optimize for public benefits.
所以我觉得一切是从这里开始 然后层层向下传导
So really, I think it starts from there and it ladders down from there.
对我们来说 我们的宗旨和使命 归根结底是要确保人类向
For us, our purpose, our mission ultimately is to make sure that the transition to
强大 AI 过渡的过程顺利 并且对人类整体是有正面收益的
powerful AI goes well and is net beneficial for humanity.
我觉得在公司内部 我们
We, I think, internally,
都对此非常振奋
we are very excited.
而且我觉得说实话
And I think, honestly,
我们对这件事未来能发展到什么程度非常非常乐观
we're very, very optimistic about where this can go.
但我们也清楚其中的风险是什么
But we also understand what the risks are.
所以对我们来说，最首要的目标就是这件事必须对人类有好的结果
And so for us, that top line objective of this just needs to go well for humanity.
这件事必须对人类有好的结果
This just needs to go well for humanity.
为了这一点，我们愿意承受重大的商业损失
That is something that we are happy to take a significant commercial hit for.
而且我们一再这么做 对吧
And we've done that time and time again, right?
就是说我们确实是这么做的 你知道
So like we have it, you know,
比如当时 好
like back then, okay,
你已经有了 Claude 但你不想发布它 因为你会觉得
you had Claude, but you don't want to release it because you're like,
这里面存在安全风险
there's a safety risk.
所以我一次又一次看到
And so there's time and time again that I've seen,
我们愿意承受这样的代价
we've been happy to take that hit.
而且事实证明 这在其他方面对我们反而是有利的
And it's actually worked out well for us in other ways.
从增长的视角来看
From like a growth lens,
我会把这件事看成是
you know, I look at it as like,
增长团队经常会去突破什么算是良好用户体验的边界
growth teams can often push the boundaries of what is like a good user UX,
等等 因为他们会非常非常
et cetera, because they're trying to very,
拼命地在某些时候挤出一点点指标提升
very much like eke out metrics at times.
当我在想 如果有人拿一个有争议的实验来找我
When I think about if a controversial test is brought to me,
我大概会这样来看待它
I sort of look at it as like this.
有两种类型的有争议实验
There's two types of tests that are controversial.
一种是这个实验争议大到你根本就不该做
One is when that test is so controversial that you just should not run the thing because
因为结果根本无关紧要
the results don't matter.
因为无论结果如何 你都不会上线它 出于多方面考虑 比如
Because you would not ship it for a combination of,
品牌 以及对客户的友好程度和价值观
you know, brand and sort of customer friendliness and values.
第二种是 它确实有争议
And then the second is where it's like, it's controversial.
比如说 我不喜欢它
Like, I don't like it.
我肯定谈不上喜欢
I certainly don't love it.
但它又没有到红线的程度
But it's like, it's not like a red line.
所以你会觉得
And so you're like, you know,
如果有人非常有信心地来跟你说
if someone comes to you with conviction and is like,
我对这件事有一个非常好的假设
I have a really good hypothesis around this,
而你会觉得 我并不喜欢
and you're like, I don't love it.
但你可以去做这个实验 看看它会带来什么影响
But like, you can run the test and see what impact it has.
而如果说 它带来的那种
And if it's like, if it's like a high level of like,
尴尬感或恶心感非常强 那我就希望它在结果上能带来非常高的回报
cringe or ick, then I want to see a high level of return for the result for that.
我基本上会把所有事情都想成
I kind of think about everything in like,
它属于第一类 还是第二类
is it in one or is it in two?
而对每家公司来说
And for every company,
这两类的划分标准都不一样
that one and two is different.
对我们来说 AI 安全非常明确地属于第一类
I think for us, the AI safety is like very much in one.
我觉得这就像是
I think that it's like,
对 这就是我们存在的原因
yeah, that's why we exist.
所以没问题
Like, yeah, it's fine.
我们就是不会去做这件事
We're just not going to do this thing.
我觉得还有一些事情属于第二类 你会对它格外敏感
I think there's other things that fall into two where you're like heightened sensitivity,
但我们可以试一试 看看会发生什么
but we can try it and see what happens.
不过如果把视角拉远一点
I think zooming out though,
Lenny 我觉得我看到增长团队犯的最大错误之一
Lenny, one of the biggest mistakes I feel like I see growth teams make,
尤其是那些特别“硬核”的增长从业者
and particularly just like hardcore growth practitioners,
就是试图把最后一分钱都挤出来
is just trying to squeeze every last dollar.
我觉得这在生活中也是一个普遍原则
It's just like, I think it's like a general principle also in life.
如果你是一个在融资的创业者 / 创始人
If you're a founder raising money,
你要是也想把投资人最后一块钱都挤出来
you're just trying to squeeze that last dollar.
在我看来 你不该这么做 因为你还希望他们下次再回来
You don't want to do that because you want people to come back next time as well, is my view.
在增长这件事上也是一样
And I think in growth,
我觉得非常重要的一点是 你要能接受桌上留点钱不赚
I think it's really important that you just need to be okay leaving money on the table.
这对我们增长团队来说是一个核心原则
And that's a core principle for us as a growth team,
我们非常乐于放弃一些指标提升 来优先保证安全
where we are very comfortable foregoing metric impact in order to prioritize safety,
为了保护我们的品牌
in order to protect our brand,
为了维持高质量标准 并保持出色的用户体验
in order to hold a high quality bar and to maintain a great user experience.
如果你把目光放到短期之外
And if you look beyond the short term and like,
不只是盯着 本季度的数据是多少
okay, what are the numbers for this quarter?
而是拉远去想想 这个世界上最好的产品是什么样的
And you zoom out and you think about what are the very best products out there,
你会发现它们都是这样运作的
you realize this is how they all operate.
而这其实才是长期推动更多增长的关键
And that's actually the thing that's going to drive more growth long term as well.
所以我觉得这又回到了安全这个话题
And so I think that actually ties back to safety,
随着风险越来越高 利害关系越来越大
where as the risks get higher and the stakes get higher,
我认为 我们在安全上明确表态 并把它视为我们工作核心这一点
I think the fact that we are taking a stance and safety is critical to what we do is
实际上会成为我们非常重要的竞争优势
actually going to become a significant competitive advantage for us that I think is going
我觉得这会在长期帮助我们
to help us in the long run.
听你讲完这些
Yeah, as you share all this,
很明显这套做法是奏效的
like clearly it's working.
Anthropica is killing it.
Anthropic 表现非常出色
所以我很喜欢有人用这种方式来解决问题
So I love when someone approaching a problem that way,
而且事实证明确实行得通
it actually works out.
我对自己的电子通讯 / Newsletter 也是同样的想法
That's the same way I think about with my newsletter.
我还能做很多事情来让它增长
There's so much more I can do to grow it.
但我的理念就是
My philosophy is just like,
只要专注于创作好的内容
just focus on creating good content,
这些微小的优化到最后其实都无关紧要
like all these micro optimizations are not going to matter in the end.
如果内容对他们有用 它就会通过人们的分享自然增长
It'll grow through people sharing it if it's useful to them.
所以在一个非常小的尺度上
So in a very small scale,
我有着类似的理念
I have a similar philosophy.
在我们聊天的时候 很多人可能在想一件事
One of the things that people are probably thinking about as we talk,
我们会开玩笑说 AI 会在各处取代工作的一部分
so, you know, we joke about like AI replacing parts of jobs here and there.
但你知道 对很多人来说这其实挺可怕的
Like, you know, it is pretty scary to a lot of people.
就是 我的工作未来会怎样
Just like, what is the future of my job?
我还会有工作吗
Will I have a job?
在这样的未来里 我该如何保持自己的价值
How do I stay relevant in this future?
所以这里其实有几个问题
So there's a couple of questions here.
其中一个是 对那些想在即将到来的 AI 时代中活得很好的人来说
One is just like, for folks that want to thrive in this approaching AI future,
无论是作为产品经理 还是增长从业者
as a PM, as a growth person,
你有没有什么建议
do you have any advice,
他们现在应该开始做些什么
things that they should be doing right now?
对我来说 会想到几件事
To me, a couple of things come up.
比如大家都会说 要去用这些工具
Like one thing that everyone says is like, use the tools.
你需要真正熟练掌握这些工具
You need to be on top of the tools.
我觉得你需要开始使用代码
I think you need to be using code.
你需要在用 Cowork，并且真正理解每一次模型发布
You need to be using Cowork and understanding just each model release.
你现在可以用它做哪些新的事情
What is the new things you can do with this?
你要怎么把这些应用到你的工作中
How can you apply this to your job?
在有些事情上它会表现得很好
It'll work well in some things.
在另外一些事情上它会表现得很糟糕
It'll work terribly in other things.
然后再过一次模型发布
And then one model launch later,
你会发现，天哪，之前那个事情现在居然能行了
it's like, oh shit, that other thing worked.
但如果你没有回去再试一次
But if you didn't go back to try it,
你就根本不会知道这点
you would not have known.
然后很多个月就这样过去了
And now many months have passed,
所以你一直不知道那其实是可行的
so you didn't know that that was possible.
所以我认为时刻跟上这些工具真的非常重要
And so I think that being on top of the tools is really important,
既是为了提升你自己的生产力
both for improving your own productivity,
也是为了培养你对 AI 产品的产品直觉
but also for getting product sense around AI products,
而我认为这只会变得越来越重要
which I think is just going to become increasingly important.
然后如果再往外拉远一点看
I think then zooming out beyond that,
我有点把这件事看成是
I kind of look at it as like,
要主动靠向你拥有竞争优势和不对称优势的地方
just leaning into where you have a competitive advantage and an unfair advantage.
对我来说就是
And so to me, it's like,
有些人，有些产品经理在所谓的专业技艺方面真的很擅长
there are some people, some PMs who are really good at like craft,
比如说，还有一些人你把他丢进一个场景里
for example, and there's others who you throw them into a situation with all these
里面一堆利益相关方，每个人意见都特别强烈
stakeholders who have all these strong opinions.
看起来根本不可能调和这些分歧，但他们最后出来的时候
And there's no way they're going to mediate this and they come out and it's like
所有人都已经大致朝着同一个正确方向在游了
everyone's kind of swimming in the right direction.
所以如果你去想一想
And so if you think about like,
你在哪一项核心技能上特别突出，并且这项技能能直接关联到
what is the major skill set that you have where you spike in that can be tied to
在公司和产品岗位上真正交付、推动影响力
delivering, driving impact for a company and product role?
我会建议你就加倍押注在那件事上
I would just double down on that and like,
几乎可以先把自己的弱项都放一边
almost like forget the weaknesses.
想的是，你要怎么在那件事上做到几乎是最顶尖的人
Just what can you do to become like the best person at that thing?
因为那样的价值非常非常高
Because that's like very, very valuable.
而且我觉得这也呼应了一个观点，就是要主动拥抱跨学科
And I think that ties to the notion of just leaning into being interdisciplinary.
回到我们前面提到的一些内容
So going back to some of what we mentioned earlier on,
就是那种，好
where it's like, okay,
在这个工程师同时又像迷你 PM 的世界里
in this world of engineers and mini PMs,
那些极具产品思维的工程师就是独角兽
that the engineer who is like highly product-minded is a unicorn,
绝对的独角兽
is an absolute unicorn.
我觉得对产品经理也是一样
I think the same thing is true for PMs where it's like,
在现在这种人员配比下
okay, now in this ratio,
如果设计资源非常吃紧，而你是一个会做设计的 PM
if the design is really stressed and you're a PM who can design,
那你现在同样也是独角兽
you are also a unicorn now.
公司愿意把你裁掉的概率会大幅下降，因为你
Like the chances of a company letting you go has gone down dramatically because you are
现在变得有用得多
now just so much more useful.
所以我觉得这一点真的非常非常重要
And so I think that is just like really, really important.
如果我回头看对我自己最有帮助的是什么
I think if I look at what's benefited me,
大概也是这个思路的某种版本
it's probably a version of this.
对我来说，这来自于我做创业者 / 创始人的背景
I think that for me, it came from a founder background.
所以是创业者 / 创始人的经历
So like the mix of the founder background,
再加上金融，我之前是投行从业者
the finance, I was an investment banker,
所以有金融背景、对数字很敏感
so like the finance background and numbers,
还有销售，我当时差点去做销售代表，而不是进产品
and then sales, I almost became an account exec instead of going into product.
我当时就在那个分叉点上
I was right on the edge of,
在纠结要去做销售还是做产品
should I go into sales or product?
我觉得把这些再加上增长，组合在一起
And I think a combination of those along with growth is probably what's led to there are
就会让我在某些领域和场景下，能产生远超他人的影响力
certain areas and situations where I can just have outsized impact to other people.
所以弄清楚对你来说那是什么，非常重要
And so understanding what that is for you is really important.
比如我看我们的金融服务类产品
I look at our financial services product,
you know, we've launched like Claude for Sheets, Claude for Excel.
你知道的，我们上线了 Claude for Sheets、Claude for Excel 之类的
顺便说一句，它们简直要把市场打趴下了
They got to like tank the market, by the way.
我知道，但负责这个产品的那个人
I know. But like the guy running that,
Nick Lin, like he came from investment banking,
Nick Lin，他来自投行
做过私募股权
he came from private equity,
所以在做这类产品时，他有巨大的竞争优势
and he just has such a competitive advantage where he's building that product.
他会说，这个我懂，这个我也懂
And he's like, I know this, I know this.
他简直就是为这件事而生的
He's like built for this.
所以我觉得，弄清楚有哪些跨学科的交叉地带是你可以主动靠过去的
And so I think just understanding what are those interdisciplinary areas you can lean into
让你自己变得
to make yourself more,
影响力更大，这点非常重要
just like higher impact is really important.
最后一点就是要有适应性
And then the last one is just being adaptable.
任何还在一味套用旧打法的人
Anyone who is trying to just keep applying old playbooks,
我觉得只会让自己的日子变得更难
I think you're going to make life a lot harder for yourself.
所以加入 Anthropic 之后最重要的一件事之一是，你得意识到
So one of the biggest things you come into Anthropic is you need to understand that
可能吧，是的，大概有你过去运作方式的五成、六成、七成
probably, yeah, 50, 60, 70% of how you operate in the past,
都得直接扔出门外
just throw it out the door.
它们已经不再适用
It's not going to be relevant.
如果你还想死守那些东西
And if you try to stick to that,
你会遇到很多阻力，而且一点帮助都没有
you're going to have a lot of friction and it's not going to be helpful.
所以要保持适应性，并且意识到
So just being adaptable and understanding,
好，工作已经朝这个方向变了
OK, the job's changed this way.
那我也要往那个方向走
I'm going to go that way,
我觉得这真的非常非常重要
is I think like it's so, so important.
这些建议太棒了
That is awesome advice.
这和 Jenny 来上播客时分享的很多内容非常契合
It matches a lot of what Jenny shared when she came on the podcast,
她是负责 Claude、Claude Work 等这些项目的设计负责人
the design leader on Claude and Claude Work and all these things.
我特别喜欢“往深处钻”这个理念
I would just like like the idea of going deep,
在某个非常具体的领域做到最好或数一数二，哪怕不是每家公司
becoming the best or one of the best at a very specific thing and that not every company
都一直需要这项能力，你自己也不一定时时都用得上
will need and you don't need all time,
但就是在某件事上钻得足够深
but just going deep on something.
我忘了她当时是怎么形容的了
I forget how she described it.
还有 Driessen 其实也说过同样的话
Or again, Driessen said the same thing.
我记得我们当时把它叫做“横着的 E 型”，而不是只有一条竖线的 T 型
Just like I think we called it a sideways E instead of just like T-shaped of one thing.
如果你能在好几件事情上都特别特别擅长
If you could have a couple of things you're really, really good at.
那会非常有力量
There's a lot of power to that.
哦，天哪，好
Oh, man. OK.
在我讲一件我觉得会让很多人震惊的事之前——关于我们是怎么认识的
Before I get into something that I think will blow a lot of people's minds about how we
以及这在你整个旅程中占了多大一部分
actually met and kind of a big part of your journey,
我先问你一个问题
let me just ask you this.
关于 Anthropic 还有什么值得分享的东西吗
Is there anything else about Anthropic that might be worth sharing,
或许值得聊一聊这个
might be worth talking about?
我首先想到的大概就是我们的文化以及在这里一起工作的人
The thing that maybe comes to mind is just like our culture and the people that we have here.
我真的觉得这是我们的秘密武器
I really think it's our secret sauce.
我认为这是我们最具防御力的东西
I think it's the thing that is the most defensible,
是别人根本没法复制的东西
the thing that no one else is going to be able to replicate.
而且我不觉得这是偶然的
And I don't think it's an accident.
领导层在这方面投入了非常多
Leadership has really invested in this a lot.
而且丹尼尔和达里奥他们俩真的非常相信这一点
And Daniel and Dario, they really believe in this a lot.
他们确实打造出了一种非常特别的文化
And they've just created a very special culture.
所以我会说这真的是一家使命驱动的公司
So I would say that this is truly a mission-driven company.
而我刚加入的时候并不是百分之百确定这一点
And I was not 100% sure of that when I joined.
我当时觉得这是一家很令人兴奋的公司
I think that this is an exciting company.
我非常认同他们的原则
I very much agree with their principles,
但我在公司里一个人都不认识
but I didn't know anyone at the company.
我也没有任何关于公司内部是什么样子的参考
I didn't have any references on what it was like inside.
所以刚加入的时候我有点怀疑
So I was a little skeptical when I joined.
我当时想的是，至少他们在谈这些
I'm like, at least they're talking about it.
但我不知道，他们到底是不是认真的
But I don't know, are they serious about this?
然后我一进来没多久
And then I came in very early.
我就心想，哦，哇靠
I was like, oh, oh, shit.
好吧，也许他们在内部对这件事的重视程度比对外说的还要高
Okay, maybe they're even more serious about this internally than they talk externally.
所以就会变成这样
And so it's just like,
这是一家使命驱动的公司，人们在直觉层面上
it's a mission-driven company where people viscerally,
在直觉层面上理解这项技术的利与弊
viscerally understand both the upsides and the downsides of the technology,
因而也理解这件事对人类未来可能走向的巨大分歧范围
and therefore understand the divergent ranges of how this may go for humanity,
以及那会带来多么截然不同的未来
and how different of a future that could be.
而当你真正理解这一点时
And I think when you understand that,
理解这对我们所有人的未来会有多么不同
of how different this could be as a future for all of us,
包括我们的孩子和孙辈
and like our children and our grandchildren,
等等时，我觉得这会让大家对自己在做的事情充满热情
etc, I think it leads to a lot of passion for what we do.
也会让大家对我们正在做的事情有很强的信念
And it just leads to a lot of belief in what we're doing.
所以我会回头看看我以前做过的每一份工作
And so I kind of look at every other job I've had in the past.
在那些公司里，总有一部分人已经心不在焉
There's some degree of people at the company who are just checked out,
就是那种，你懂的
where it's like, you know,
我人在这儿，但我已经受够了
I'm here, I'm sick of this,
但我也没有更好的选择
but I don't have a better option,
或者说我拿的钱太多，不好意思走之类的
or I'm getting paid too much to leave, etc.
而在这里，完全不是这样
That is just like, not the case here.
我一个这样的人都没遇到过
I have not met a single person.
我是说，一个已经躺平的人都没有
I'm saying a single person who's checked out.
每个人都把自己所有的东西都摆在桌面上
Everyone is putting everything they have on the table.
每个人都在全力以赴
Everyone is pouring it out and like,
毫无保留，整个人完全投入进去
leaving nothing behind and is just fully, fully in it.
所以我觉得这会释放出一种能量，这种能量非常
And so I think that leads to like this releases energy that is just like very,
非常难以言喻
very hard to describe.
你一方面有这种能量
I think you have that energy,
一方面有这种使命驱动的特质
you have that mission driven nature,
再加上这是一个极其开放的文化
and then it's such an open culture.
所以领导层在很多事情上都非常
So leadership is very,
非常对我们透明
very transparent with us on things.
我们这边的 Slack 就像是
We, Slack is like a, it's a,
一个巨大的迷宫
it's a whole maze.
太多事情都在 Slack 上发生
There's so many things that play out on Slack.
我们非常开放，每个人都有自己的 notebook 频道，有点像你自己的 Twitter
We're very open. Everyone has these notebook channels where you kind of have like your own like Twitter
时间线，在上面随时分享你对各种事情的想法
feed in a way where you're just talking about your thoughts about things.
所以你可以去加入别人的 Slack 频道
And so you can go and like join the Slack channel,
加入做研究的人以及其他各个领域同事的 notebook 频道
the notebook channels of people on research and all these other areas.
这样你想学什么都可以去看
And like, you can learn whatever you want,
你也可以花很多时间沉浸在里面
and you can spend so much time getting lost in that as well.
但正是这种开放，在这里我们被鼓励
But that, that openness where we've been encouraged,
比如说，大家可以直接和 Dario 争论
like people can just argue with Dario.
有一次全员大会
There was an all hands.
你说了句话，有人不认同
You said something where someone didn't agree.
然后那个人就跑到 Dario 的 notebook 频道上直接说
And then, and the person goes onto Dario's notebook channel and just says like,
嘿，我不太认同你刚才那样说这个那个
Hey, I didn't appreciate how you said this and this and that.
然后这就引发了一场大讨论
And then it sparked a whole big debate.
呃，但就是这种事情
Um, but like that sort of thing where like,
是被鼓励的，你可以去找领导公开表达不同意见，公开挑战他们
it's encouraged, like go to leadership and disagree with them, challenge them publicly.
而这种氛围会带来一种信任感，再加上前面说的那些
And like that, I think that just leads to a level of trust and all of that together.
我觉得这意味着我们拥有一种非常
I think it just means that we have this very,
非常深的团结感
very deep sense of togetherness that,
呃，天哪，我以前真的从来没有
um, man, I have just like never,
从来没有经历过类似的东西
I've never experienced anything like it.
然后再说到人才，对吧
And, and then you get to the talent, right?
我觉得在人才密度这件事上
I think that is the thing where the talent density is like,
有时候我感觉自己像是在为皇家马德里效力
I feel like I'm playing for like Real Madrid at times.
我环顾四周就会想
I look around, I'm like,
天啊，我真的是在为皇马踢球吧
man, I'm playing for Madrid, right?
就是那种，你身边都是世界上最顶尖的人
It's like, you just like have the best people in the world.
我觉得在研究团队里这一点最明显
I think it's most, I think it's most the case on research.
我们有那些真正
We have like the very,
世界上最顶尖的研究人员
very best researchers in the world.
但就算你看产品这边
But even you look on like product,
我们有 Ami Vora 在这里 就是特别厉害
we have Ami Vora. Like she is phenomenal.
我们这儿有迈克·克里格 你就会想 好家伙 随随便便就创办了 Instagram
We have Mike Krieger. You're like, okay, casually started Instagram.
他现在在这儿，嗯，然后在增长这边
He's here, um, you know, on growth.
我们有 John Egan，他是我在工程上的对口搭档
We have John Egan, who is my engineering counterpart.
他算是增长工程领域的元老级人物
He's like the OG in growth engineering.
他真的、真的非常厉害
He's, he's, he's, he's great.
我们还有 Alexei，他是在 Reforge 教增长工程的那个人
We have Alexei. He's like guy who teaches growth engineering at Reforge.
而在我们团队里他就只是另一个同事
He's just like another dude on the team.
呃 而这一切加在一起，我觉得都非常特别
Um, and all of that, I think is just very special.
我最喜欢的一个小故事是，几个月前在 Linear 上
My favorite here is like in the Linear a couple of months ago,
我们十月开了全公司线下大会，我在现场四处走
we had our onsite company wide onsite and in October and I'm walking around,
我看到有个家伙一个人边走边吃爆米花
I see these guys just walking around eating popcorn by himself.
我走过去跟他说，你是 Jeff，对吧
I go up to him and I'm like, you're Jeff, right?
他就说，是的
And he's like, I am.
我当时心里想，你简直就是我祖国澳大利亚的美国大使
And I'm like, you are literally the US ambassador to my country, Australia.
而你在这里却只是个普通员工
And you're just an employee here.
我就觉得，这也太疯狂了
I'm like, this is insane.
我会去跟我们国家的总理之类的人物对话
I'm like talking to our prime ministers of our country and all these things.
正是这种人才再加上那种文化
And it's just the talent combined with that culture,
我觉得就是这道“秘密酱料”
I think is just this secret source that,
呃 也是我认为我们能取得如今成功的原因
uh, is, is, is the reason that I think we are as successful as we are.
这个 notebook 频道特别有意思
This notebook channel is so interesting,
就作为一个战术层面的工具来说
just like as a tactical thing.
它的想法是 Dario 会在上面分享
So the idea there is Dario just shares,
有点像一个迷你版 Twitter
it's like a little Twitter,
就是一个内部的 Twitter 信息流 大家会在上面分享自己在想什么
like internal Twitter feed where folks just share what they're thinking about and what
以及他们当前的优先事项之类的东西
their, what their priorities are and things like that.
对 基本上就是这样
Yeah, that's basically it where it's,
它是一个内部信息流 不只是 Dario 每个人都有一个
it's an internal feed where it's not just Dario, everyone has one.
你基本上就是在上面分享自己的内部想法
And you basically, you share your internal thoughts.
这是一种方式 可以让大家随时了解哪些事情在起作用
It's a way to like, keep people updated on things on what's working.
也是一个人们会分享一些有点挑衅性观点的地方
It's a way where people share provocative things,
我觉得更多是从领导层的角度出发
I think from like a leadership level.
我们也把它看作是一种在组织内部放大你信念和观点的方式
And we also think about that as it's a way to scale your beliefs and views across an org
尤其是在组织快速扩张的时候
as it grows quickly, right?
所以说 当你在组织里不断增加很多新人的时候
So like, if you're not adding a lot of people in the organization,
你就需要去思考
you need to think about,
好 我们想要示范哪些行为
okay, what are the like behaviors that we want to model?
哪些原则是我们最看重的
What are the principles that are top of mind to us?
如果你再往下想
And if you think about like,
当然 你可以开一堆会来讨论这些
yeah, you can have a bunch of these meetings where you talk about it,
你可以通过行为去示范
you can, you can model that behavior.
但如果你有这样一个频道
But if you have a channel,
用来写“这是我现在最关心的事”
which is like, here's my top of mind,
然后你把这些东西写出来
and you say these things, right?
比如说我发了一篇帖子
Like if I have a post,
就像我前几周发的那样
which I did the other week of like,
讲的是“为什么要习惯于敢于把钱留在桌上不去拿”的重要性
this is the importance of being comfortable leaving money on the table.
现在所有新加入增长团队的工程师都看到了 就会想
Now all the new engineers on growth who've joined have seen that and they're like,
哦 好吧 这跟我们以前的认知不太一样
oh, okay, well, this is like different to what we had,
跟我们之前习惯的做法不一样
we've known before, right?
我觉得这对开放性很有好处
I think it's like, good for the openness,
但对领导者来说 这也是一种在组织里放大自己观点的好方式
but it's also good as a leader of how you can scale your views as an organization to like,
让大家更快理解事情在这里是怎么做的
get people more up to speed on the way that things are done,
而这在我看来非常重要
which is, I think, really important to like,
为了避免那种“漂移” 因为我们有太多新成员加入 这种漂移会导致很多
avoid that drift, which we have so many new people signing up that drift can lead to a lot
在战略和认知上的偏离
of drift in strategy and sort of perception.
所以从这个角度看 它能帮助我们把这艘船掌得更稳更紧
So it just helps run a run a tighter ship in that way.
更重要的是 这也为每个人在跑的那些代理提供数据 好让它们更好地和这些人类协作
And more importantly, the data for the agents everyone's got running to help them work with all these humans.
是的 完全正确
Yes, that is very, very correct.
比如说 这些内容会被送进 Claude
Like, it is something that goes to Claude,
你知道 在入职培训里有些文档上会写着
you know, that there are certain documents in onboarding where it's like,
人力资源团队会标注
the HR team has written,
在修改这个文档里的任何内容之前
before editing anything on this document,
请先和这个人确认
please check with this person,
因为这是 Claude 会引用的一个关键文档
because this is a document that Claude references as like a key thing, right?
所以越来越多类似这样的东西
And so more and more these types of things of,
比如说 增长团队是怎么想这件事的
okay, how does the growth team think about this?
安全防护团队又是怎么想的
How do safeguards think about this?
你就是在给 Claude 提供这些上下文 让它未来在帮助大家时越来越给力
You're arming Claude with that context to get better and better at helping in the future.
这很有意思 感觉这会变成每家公司都得开始做的一件事
That's interesting. It feels like that's something that every company is going to have to start doing is just
用结构化的方式分享自己的想法 这样我们每个人在用的这些代理
sharing their thoughts in a structured way so that all these agents that we've all got
才能获得它们需要了解的信息
running have what they need to know.
另一个有意思的旁支话题是 Slack
Another interesting side note here is just Slack.
好 现在有很多人在说 SaaS 工具会被 AI 取代
Okay, so like, there's all this talk of SaaS tools being replaced by AI.
而你们在用 Slack
And you guys use Slack.
我记得有一条很有名的推文在说你们还在用 Workday 和所有这些工具、这些 SaaS 工具
I think there's this famous tweet of you guys still use Workday and all these tools, all these SaaS tools.
大家都在说 它们都会被“vibe coding”之类的东西干掉
Everyone's like, they're all going to be vibe coded out of existence.
但事实是 你们这些
The fact that you all,
站在代码能做到的最前沿的人
at the cutting edge of what could be built with code,
依然在用 Slack 和这些其他工具
still use Slack and all these other tools.
在我看来 这说明也许 SaaS 公司未来还是能活得不错
To me, that's a good sign that maybe SaaS companies will be all right in the future.
不知道你在这方面有没有什么想法可以分享
I don't know if you have anything there to share.
嗯 我觉得这个图景其实挺复杂的
Yeah, I think it's a really complicated picture, right?
有不少东西我们是自己在内部直接做的
Like there's a number of things that we just build internally ourselves.
随着时间推移 Claude 在这方面做得更好的能力也在不断提升
As time goes on, the ability for Claude to do that better increases.
但与此同时
And at the same time,
我们非常大量地使用 Figma
we use Figma a ton.
我们也非常大量地使用 Slack
We use Slack a ton.
我们用 Workday 用很多这类产品
We use Workday. We use a lot of these products.
而且我不觉得这在短期内会改变
And I don't see that changing in the immediate future.
所以呢 我觉得这些说法里确实有一部分是对的
And so, yeah, I think there's probably some truth to some of this.
但另外一部分就有点被夸大了
I think the other parts are like, it's overblown.
而且这些产品里有很多
And many of these products,
其实是我们的客户
the customers of ours,
我们非常重视他们作为客户的价值
we value them a lot as customers.
同时我们也非常大量地使用他们的产品
And we use their products very, very heavily.
而我不觉得这点会变
And I don't see that changing.
而且你还有更重要的事要做
And you have better things to do.
比如说 谁会花时间去重造一个 Slack 呢
Like, who's going to spend time building Slack?
价值不会主要积累在这种地方
That is not where value is going to accrue.
我觉得这也能让你意识到
And I think it also helps you see how much,
这些产品其实有多复杂精细
how sophisticated these things are.
它们可不是那种
They're not just like,
你知道的 随便搞搞的东西 有团队为这些问题思考了很久很久
you know, like there's been teams thinking about these problems for a long time.
总之 这又是一个完全可以展开聊的岔题
Anyway, that's a whole other tangent.
先回到价值观这个话题上
Just coming back to the values thing.
我只想在这里强调一件非常重要的事
I just want to highlight something here that's really important.
很多人批评 Anthropic 总是在谈论对人类的危险
A lot of people criticize Anthropic for talking about the dangers to humanity,
抛出各种工作岗位会消失的数据
throwing out all these numbers about jobs going away,
觉得你们是在制造恐慌
just like creating all this fear.
但很多人会觉得
But like, and people think it's,
哦 你们是在借机融资
oh, we're trying to raise money.
我们得先抓住大家的注意力
We gotta get people's attention.
不然的话，是的，我们就好像只是在制造一些吸睛的标题
Or we just, yeah, we're just trying to like create headlines.
但我在内部见到的一切始终都只是
But everything I've ever seen internally is always just,
这是我们所坚信的东西
this is what we believe in.
我们希望人们知道可能会发生什么
We want people to know what it might be coming,
即便那不一定是坏事
even if it isn't bad.
我们希望人们明白接下来可能会发生什么
We want people to understand here's what might happen.
而我们正努力去避免那些情况
And we are trying to avoid it.
你可能会说，为什么不这样
And you might say, why doesn't,
如果这东西这么危险，Anthropic 为什么还要去构建 AI
why is Anthropic even building AI if it's so dangerous?
而你知道，Ben 分享的理解大概是
And, you know, the understanding Ben shared is just like,
我们认为，与其袖手旁观只希望别出事，不如亲自下场，努力用正确的方式把它造出来
we think it's better that we go at this and try to build it the right way versus just stay
而不是置身事外，只寄望于不会发生坏事
out of it and just hope that nothing bad happens.
嗯，我这儿一下子能想到三点
Yeah, I think three things that come to mind there.
第一点，我要回到我之前说过的一件事
First is, I go back to something I said earlier,
就是我们非常习惯用指数级的视角来看问题
which is that we very much think about things from an exponential lens.
如果你是用线性的视角来看这些事
And if you are thinking about things from a Linear lens,
你看到的世界会完全不一样，对吧
you will see the world very, very differently, right?
因为你看当下的状况，你会觉得
Because you look at where we are today and you're like,
好吧，两三年之后还能好到哪儿去呢
okay, but like how much better can it be in two, three years?
但如果你用指数级的视角，并且理解
I think if you're looking at it from an exponential lens and you understand how
指数是怎么运作的，你就会意识到，很多事情其实会
exponentials work, then you just realize that a lot of this stuff is actually going to be
比那些用线性视角的人想象得更早发生
happening sooner than people think if you're looking at it from a Linear lens.
而且如果你明白这里既有上行空间也有下行风险，结果的范围可能非常大
And then if you understand that there could be upsides and downsides and the range of
那你就需要
outcomes here, you need to,
我认为我们必须认真讨论这些负面结果，这样才能避免它们，并推动事情朝好的方向发展
I think we very much need to be talking about the downsides so we can avoid them and push towards the upsides.
我觉得公司里大多数人都是乐观主义者
I think most people at the company are optimists.
我们对未来非常乐观
We're very optimistic about the future.
只是我们也明白，这里面的风险在于
I think it's just, we understand the risk is like,
没有人能保证最后一定会走向一个好的结局
it is not a guarantee that we end up in a good place.
而且现在谈论这些风险的人还远远不够
And not enough people are talking about the risks,
我指的是那些既能以建设性的方式讨论，又真正懂这些风险的人
I think in productive ways and who have the know-how of the risks.
有些人也许会谈风险
I think there's people who may talk about the risks,
但他们并不在这个赛场里
but are not in the game.
所以他们其实并不完全清楚
And so they don't actually know fully,
他们并不能非常精确地说清楚具体的风险点是什么
like they're not like surgical on what the specific risks are,
但我们是在场上的人
but we're in the game,
我们知道正在发生什么
we understand what's happening.
这是一方面
And so that's one piece.
第二点是
I think the second is like,
我觉得我们内部对这些事情的信念，其实比我们对外说出来的要更强烈
I think we actually believe in this stuff more strongly than we say externally.
它已经深深嵌入我们的内部思维方式里，以至于有时候我们会改写你的
It is just such a key part of how we think internally that sometimes we reword your
这些表述，因为
statements because it's like,
外面的人可能会觉得我们太夸张了
people might just think we're being too over the top,
但在内部，我们确实就是那样想的
but internally that's how we think.
而我们对外发布的内容，有时候只是那个想法的“柔和版”
And what we're putting out is a softer version of that at times.
第三点就回到 Ben 说的
And then I think the third piece is going to what Ben said,
我们非常在意的是把这场竞赛往“比谁做得更好”的方向推
we think a lot about driving the race to the top.
所以如果你不在场上，只是在场边大喊大叫，其实没人会在意
And so it's like, if you're not in the game and you're shouting from the sidelines, no one cares.
这就是世界运作的现实
It's just the reality of how the world works.
基本没人会真正关心
Like no one really cares.
如果你在场上，而且是领先者之一
If you're in the game and you're a leading player,
而且你做的事情确实奏效
and what you're doing is working,
你就能影响其他在场上的参与者，让他们采取更正确的行动
you can influence people who are also in the game to take the right actions.
这差不多就是核心所在
And so that is like the core of it.
如果我们现在收摊回家
Like if we just pack up and go home,
我们对这件事就完全没有任何影响力
you have no influence on this thing.
而如果你留在赛场上，而且商业上表现很好
And if you stay in the game and you're like commercially, you're doing great.
那你就有办法去施加影响
And then you have ways to influence that.
比如说，把“这些是我们的原则”带进公共讨论里
Okay, these are the principles and put that into the conversation and make more people
让更多人逐渐认同这些原则
sort of believe in those things.
Amol，我可以一直跟你聊下去
I could talk to you forever, Amol.
但我还想再问两个问题，来给这次对话收个尾，也顺便聊聊一些
But two more questions just to round out the conversation and touch on some stuff that
我之前多次暗示过的话题
I've hinted at a number of times.
其中一个是，我想把话题拉到“失败角”
One is I want to take us actually to failure corner,
因为在听的人可能会想
because someone listening to this may be like,
好嘛，你看这家伙，在这么多牛公司干过
all right, look at this guy just worked at all these amazing companies,
cold email the CPO at Anthropic,
给 Anthropic 的 CPO 发了封冷邮件
就拿到工作，上了这艘火箭船
got a job, joined this rocket ship.
一路都是向右上飙升
It's all been up into the right,
看起来一直顺风顺水
just killing it constantly.
那你职业生涯里，有没有哪段事情没成、你确实失败了的故事
What's a story from your career where things didn't work out when you failed?
以及你从那次经历中学到了什么
And what did you learn from that experience?
这样的例子我有好几个
I have a couple.
我的经历绝对不是你刚才描述的那种一路顺利
I think it's very much not that way.
我觉得走到今天，路径是非常曲折的
I feel like it was a lot of squiggly lines to get here.
最大的一次，大概就是我去创办了一家公司
The biggest I'd say is just founding a company,
融了一大笔钱
raising a bunch of money,
招了员工，最后却不得不关掉公司，告诉投资人你把他们的钱亏光了
having employees and then having to shut it down and tell your investors that you've lost
告诉他们你曾经有一个愿景，想做什么，但现在不会实现了
the money and that you had a vision of what you're going to do and that it's not going to happen.
所以我觉得那大概是最大的一次失败
And so that I think is probably the biggest one.
你要知道，我们在这件事上花了三年时间
You know, we spent three years on it.
这可不是那种“我们业余试试看”的项目
It was not like, oh, we tried something part time.
而是那种“我们全力一搏”的事情
It was like, no, we went for it.
我们干了三年
We had spent three years,
融了几百万美元
raised a couple of mil.
高峰期大概有七到十名员工
We had maybe seven to 10 employees at our biggest.
而且那是我们真心相信的事情
And it was something that we really believed in.
它是关于心理健康的，研究如何量化心理健康，以便帮助理解
It was around mental health and how you can quantify mental health to help understand or
或及早预测像广泛性焦虑、重度抑郁这样的状况
get early predictors of things like generalized anxiety, major depression.
所以那真的是我们非常非常相信的方向
So it's stuff that we really, really believed in.
但最终，你也知道
But ultimately, you know,
那时我们才二十出头
we were in our early 20s.
当时其实完全不知道自己在干什么，有很多事情现在会做得不一样
We had no idea what we were doing at the time and many things I did differently.
但那真的是一个非常
But that was just a very,
非常非常痛苦的过程
very, very painful process.
唯一比较好的一点是，我们始终让投资人掌握最新情况
I think the good thing was we kept our investors in the loop the whole time.
所以对任何正在挣扎的创业者 / 创始人来说
So to any founders who are struggling out there,
一定要按月给投资人发更新
send those monthly investor updates.
在一切顺利的时候发更新是最容易的事
It's really easy to send those when things are great.
在情况很糟的时候要发那种更新真的很难
It's really hard to send those when things are bad.
你只会一拖再拖
You just bat it down.
你得坐下来给投资人发一封更新说明为什么你上个月说的那些事情
You need to sit down and send an update to your investors about why everything you talked
全都没有按计划进行
about last month did not go to plan.
但那就是你应该做的事
But it's just the right thing to do.
它能让大家掌握情况，避免意外发生
And it keeps people in the loop and it avoids surprises.
但当你打电话给投资人说
But it's still so tough when you're then calling up the investors to be like,
嘿，我们要关掉公司了
hey, we're shutting down.
这个决定是我做的
I'm making that decision.
每个人都相信你
Everyone believed in you.
而那家公司已经成了你身份里很重要的一部分
And it becomes such a big part of the identity.
这真的非常非常难熬
It's very, very tough.
所以，那段经历真的太残酷了
So, man, that was just brutal.
就是那种特别残酷的感觉 而且我花了
Like, it's brutal. And it took me, I think,
好几年时间才真正走出来
like a number of years to truly get over.
我觉得那真的是件很难的事
I think that it's a tough thing.
但你从那段经历里得到的东西特别多，只是当下很难看出来
But you get so much from that experience that is hard to see in the moment.
我觉得如果没有那次经历
And I think without doing that,
我就不会走上现在这条路
I would not have gone into this.
之前我不是产品经理
I was not a PM before.
我当时完全不具备这些技能
I didn't have any of these skills.
我从没真正做过产品
I'd never worked on products.
我其实根本不懂怎么写冷邮件
I didn't know how to cold email, really.
所以正是通过那份工作 我学到了很多技能
And so it was through that job that I learned a ton of the skills that made this career
让这条职业道路对我来说变得可行
path viable for me.
而当你只看到当下那个时间点时 真的很难意识到这些
And it's just really hard to see that in the moment when you're looking at a point in time.
只有回头看时 把这些点连起来才容易
It's much easier to draw the line looking back.
但我自己的体会是 要记住这是一场长期博弈
But I think that would be my takeaway is just keep in mind that it's a long game.
而那些经历中的一部分
And some of those things...
比如说我现在非常感激那段经历
Like, I'm so grateful for that experience now.
甚至很感激它以失败、以那种方式收场
I'm so grateful that it failed and went that way, actually.
虽然很痛苦 但如果没有那次失败 我不会做现在在做的事
It's very painful because it wouldn't have led to what I'm doing now.
所以这确实是件很难的事
And so it's a tough thing,
但它也能带来很多正面的东西
but positives can come from it.
我很喜欢这一点 是因为很多人在职业生涯里都会有这样的时刻 他们会觉得
What I love about this is a lot of people have these times in their career where they're
一切都完了
like, it's all over.
我失败得一塌糊涂 名声也毁了 大家都指望着我
I failed in such a big way and my reputation screwed and people were counting on me.
现在他们会发现我是个冒牌货
And now they see I'm an imposter.
原来我一直都不知道自己在干什么
I never knew what I was doing after all.
现在他们终于看穿了
Now they finally see.
但看到的是
And just seeing that...
这段经历持续了三年
And this was three years.
I'm looking at your LinkedIn.
我在看你的 LinkedIn
你当时大概有七个员工之类的规模
You had seven employees, something like that.
And then it's like Masterclass, Mercury, Anthropic.
然后接下来就是 MasterClass、Mercury、Anthropic
我觉得听到这样的故事很鼓舞人心
I think it's inspiring to hear a story like that.
让人知道即使经历那样重大的失败 事情依然可以好转
To know that you can have a big failure like that and things can work out.
而且那并不是终点
And that it's not the end.
好 那在 2023 年 我本来要休陪产假 因为我妻子怀孕了
Okay, so in 2023, I was going to go on pat leave because my wife's pregnant.
然后我就想 等等
And I was just like, wait,
那我的电子通讯怎么办
what do I do with the newsletter?
我需要休息一段时间
I need to take some time off.
能休一两个月会非常棒
That would be really nice to take a month or two off.
所以我的计划是
And so my plan was, okay,
我要找一堆客座作者来写文章
I'm going to do a bunch of guest posts.
大家排队报名 我发出客座投稿的征集
People line up. I put out a call for guest posts.
人们来申请
People apply.
我挑出几篇 提前排好档期 这样我就能休假
I pick a few and then I kind of slot them in ahead of time so I could take time off.
所以我就发出了这个征集
So I put out this call.
嘿 谁想给我的电子通讯写一篇客座文章
Hey, who wants to write a guest post for my newsletter?
我收到了五百多份申请
I got 500 plus applications.
其中一份就是你投的
One of those applications was from you.
你的提案大意是 一次创伤性脑损伤如何让我成为更好的产品经理
And the pitch was essentially how a traumatic brain injury made me a better product manager.
我还记得当时读到你发来的第一版稿子
And I still remember reading the first draft you sent me.
我心里就只有一句话 卧槽
And I was just like, holy shit.
这个故事太厉害了
This story is incredible.
读的时候情绪特别强烈
It's just like you feel such feelings.
而且在具体方法层面也特别有意思、很有用
And it was just so tactically interesting and useful.
会让人觉得 哇 这真的能让我成为更好的产品经理
Like, oh, wow, this is actually going to make me a better product manager.
跟大家讲讲你经历的那次脑损伤 以及你之后走过的那段旅程
Share the story of the brain injury that you went through and just the journey that you
因为这个故事真的会震撼到很多人
went on there, because this is going to blow people's minds.
那是我人生中最艰难的一段时间
It was the toughest time in my life.
它让我觉得 关掉一家公司
It made shutting down a company be like,
哦 原来那根本不算什么
oh, that was nothing, actually.
视角的变化真是很有意思
It's just funny how perspective works that way.
在 2022 年年初
I back in early 2022,
我遭遇了一次创伤性脑损伤
I had a traumatic brain injury.
我练综合格斗已经很多年了
So I'd done MMA for many years.
我也练泰拳这种武术很多年
I'd done Muay Thai, which is a type of martial arts for many years.
一直都没出过问题
Never had a problem.
然后就像那种总会发生的事一样
And just it's just like one of the things that happens,
一次不对的训练 一次不对的对抗
like the wrong session, the wrong.
那天只是很普通的一次对打
It's just a normal day of sparring.
没有什么特别激烈 只是头部在不对的角度挨了一下不对的击打
Nothing crazy. You get the wrong hit to the head in the wrong way.
然后我的整个人生就变了
And my whole life changed.
基本上 我接下来花了九个月时间
And basically, I spent nine months.
有整整九个月没法工作
I was off work for nine months.
前几个月特别难熬
The first couple of months were brutal.
大概花了半年时间 我才重新走路走得比较舒服
It took me roughly half a year till I was comfortable walking again.
那段时间非常非常艰难
It was very, very difficult.
前两三个月 除了自己洗澡和上厕所之外
The first two, three months beyond just showering and going to the bathroom,
其他所有事情都是我妻子帮我做的
my wife did everything for me,
包括帮我给朋友发短信这种事
like including like texting my friends.
我听音乐大概二十秒就会觉得想吐
I would listen to music for maybe like 20 seconds and feel like I needed to vomit.
我完全没法看任何屏幕
I couldn't look at screens at all.
康复过程非常非常漫长
And it was a very, very long recovery.
有一段时间 我完全不确定自己还能不能再工作
It was not clear to me that I would ever work again for a while, actually.
甚至我和妻子还讨论过
And it was like we even discussed with my wife,
如果真那样了 我们该怎么办之类的问题
like what would we do in that case, etc.
我们不得不从那种层面去思考 而我也只能不断逼自己努力撑过去
And we had to think even on those levels and through a lot of pushing and really working through myself.
你必须慢慢提高自己对各种事情的耐受度
And you have to just slowly increase your tolerance to things.
这是一个非常残酷的过程
It's a brutal process,
但你需要慢慢让自己接触不同的事情，并在每一件事上不断变得更好
but you need to slowly expose yourself to different things and just get better and better
在每一件小事上都是如此
at each little thing.
要主动去练习这一点
Actively work on that.
不要把自己逼得太狠
Don't push it too far.
否则你会遭遇一次巨大的倒退
Otherwise, you have a big setback.
但基本上后来发展到持续了九个多月
But it basically got to the point then where it was over nine months.
然后在那之后我回去工作了，情况也就慢慢好转
And then after that, I returned to work and then it slowly got better.
还有一部分你不知道的，Lenny
And the part, Lenny, you don't know is,
你知道，在 2023 年年中
you know, we in mid 2023,
我们发出了那封电子通讯 / Newsletter
we posted that newsletter.
而在那之后一个月，我其实又受伤了
And a month later, I got re-injured, actually.
因为当你有脑损伤时
Because when you have a brain injury,
在你 100% 痊愈之前
until you're 100% healed,
你再次发生脑震荡或脑损伤的风险会升高
your risk of another concussion or brain injury is elevated.
当你 100% 痊愈时
When you're 100% healed,
你的风险才会降到和从未脑震荡过的人一样的水平
your risk falls down to that of a non-concussed population.
但在那之前，即使你已经恢复了 95%
But until that time, and you're 95% healed,
你也还没有真正 100% 痊愈
you're not 100% healed.
而那次只是日常生活中看似无害的一件小事
And it was just innocuous in everyday life,
下飞机时，一个包砸到了我的头上之类的情况
getting off a plane, a bag hit me on the head type thing.
而那时我加入 Mercury 才一个月，就又休了两个月的病假
And I was off work for two months when I had one month into joining Mercury.
入职一个月，我就只能说
One month in, I'm like,
抱歉各位，我得消失三个月
sorry, guys, I need to peace out for three months.
然后接下来是一个非常
And then it was a very,
非常漫长的康复过程
very long recovery from that.
而且事实上我现在仍然没有 100% 痊愈
And I'm actually still not 100% healed.
所以整体来说我大致还好
So I'm mostly good.
但有时候我还是会头晕、头痛，还有其他需要想办法应对的问题
But I have times when I have dizziness and headaches and other things I need to work around.
总体来说，我觉得这是发生在我身上最好的事情之一
Overall, I feel like it's one of the best things that could have happened to me.
而我认为保持这种心态很有帮助
And I think that keeping that mindset helps.
当然，这种看法也可能被推得太远，以至于脱离现实
And there's a point when you can take that too far when that view is detached from reality.
但我觉得这确实让我作为一个人变得更好、更有效率
But I think it's just made me so much better and more effective as a person.
许多相同的习惯
A lot of the same habits,
比如我不喝酒
like I don't drink alcohol,
我也不摄入咖啡因
I don't drink caffeine.
为了身体健康，我必须做一堆这样的事情
I have to do a bunch of these things for my physical health.
我就是得去做
I just have to do them.
所以我一直坚持做下去
So I keep doing them.
我会休息，这一点非常重要
I take breaks. This is like a really big one.
你可能会想，在 Anthropic 这样的地方
You might think even in a place like Anthropic,
你怎么还能这样活下去
like, how do you survive in this way?
就是说，即使在最疯狂的日子里
It's like, even on the craziest days,
Lenny，在一天开始到午饭之间，以及午饭到一天结束之间
Lenny, between the start of the day and lunch and between lunch and the end of the day,
我都会休息一小会儿
I take a short break.
即使是在最疯狂的、比如模型发布的那些日子
Even on the craziest days with like model launches,
等等，我很幸运办公室里有一个冥想区，我会去那里
etc, I'm lucky we have like a meditation area in the office that I'll go to.
然后还有我在那篇文章里提到的，关于冥想的整套东西
And then the whole side of things around meditation that I talked about in that post.
我记得你我都在 Spirit Rock 参加过禅修营，而参加冥想静修改变了我的人生
I think both you and I have done a retreat at Spirit Rock and doing a meditation retreat changed my life.
这也是我现在每年至少会做一次的事情
And it's something that I do at least once a year now.
我最近也还有一次要去
I have one coming up relatively soon as well.
我觉得所有这些都帮助我更好地管理身体层面的状况，因为
And I think all of that has helped with better managing the physical side of it because
这份工作对人消耗非常大
this job is very taxing.
而在情绪上，你也需要和发生的一切之间留出一点空间
And then emotionally having a little bit of space to what happens.
就像一边是你的觉察
Like, you have sort of awareness on one side,
另一边是现实本身
you have the reality on the other side.
而这里的现实真的很疯狂
And reality is crazy here, man.
真的，现实简直疯狂
Like, reality is insane.
每天都有太多事情在发生
Like, there's so much happening every day.
而且噪音也非常多
And there's so much noise.
这一切会让人震撼，所以觉察与现实之间的那种关系
It's mind-blowing. And so that relationship between awareness and reality,
就是你拥有选择的地方，而你会在深度冥想中学到如何调整
that's where you have choice that you sort of learn from deep meditation on how to shift
并在那一层面运用你的选择
that and apply your choice there.
我认为正是这一点，在让我保持更冷静的头脑方面给了我极大的帮助
I think that that is the thing that has helped me significantly with just keeping a more level head.
我觉得要在这样强度的环境里长期待下去，很大一部分就是要守住你的心智
I think a lot of staying in this game at this level of intensity is just keep your head.
在最疯狂的时候也不要失去理智
Just don't lose your head in the crazy times.
而我觉得我经历的这一切，都帮助我做到这一点，而不用诉诸那些不健康的应对方式
And I think all of that that I've gone through has helped me do this without resorting to unhealthy coping mechanisms.
哇
Wow.
Amol，你在太多方面都很鼓舞人心
Amol, you're such an inspiration in so many ways.
有太多理由足以让你失败、让一切无法顺利发生
There's so many reasons that you would not have been successful and things would not have worked out.
而光是从你分享的这些故事和你走过的这段旅程中
And there's so many lessons to learn from just the stories you've shared and the journey
就有太多可以学习的东西，可以帮助人们克服他们面临的挑战
you've been on to help people overcome challenges they're having.
如果你能从那样疯狂的一个……中走回来
If you can come back from an insane...
那是被人一脚踢到头上吗
Was it like a kick to the head?
是那样发生的吗
Is that what happened?
是的，是一脚踢到头上
It was a kick to the head.
没错，就是那样，从觉得自己可能再也听不了音乐
That's correct, yes. Just feeling like you may not be able to listen to music,
到现在在历史上增长最快的公司负责增长
to just leading growth at the fastest growing company in history.
这里还有一个关于约束的教训
There's also just a lesson here of constraints.
你又一次提到了这个观点：约束的力量
Again, you mentioned this idea of just the power of constraints.
你被迫去休息
You're forced to take breaks.
你被迫去冥想，而这其实非常有帮助
You're forced to go meditate in a way that's really helpful.
这对我们所有人都是一个启示
And it's a lesson for us all.
这对我们所有人其实都非常有益
This is actually really good for us all.
是的，我觉得“通过约束获得自由”是那段时间我得到的一个重要收获
Yeah, I think that freedom through constraints is one of the big takeaways I've had during that time.
因为当你有了这些约束时
Because when you have these constraints,
你就被迫去适应
you're forced to adapt.
而在商业环境中，这会让你
And it gives you, in a business setting,
在个人层面上也不得不更加专注
you have to focus more in a personal setting.
如果这个约束是
If the constraint is,
我什么都做不了，而且我受伤了
I can't do anything and I'm injured,
我不知道接下来会发生什么
I don't know what's going to happen.
我不知道自己会不会好起来
I don't know if I'm going to get better.
你只有两个选择
You have two choices.
其一是，你要不要去抗拒、去和现实对抗，然后因此承受巨大的痛苦
You're like, one, are you just going to resist and fight with reality and really suffer from that?
还是你要接受这个处境，不让它在情绪上拖垮你
Or are you going to accept the situation and not let that affect you emotionally?
这并不是说
It's not to say like,
我什么都做对了，兄弟
I did everything, man.
而是说，我当时几乎把自己能做的每一件事都做了
I was like, every single thing I could do,
饮食、锻炼之类的，我就想，好，我全都照做
diet, exercise, I was like, I'm on it.
只要是我能做的事，我都会去做
Every action I can take, I'm on it.
但接下来你要做一个选择
But then you have a choice of,
你要不要让这些事情的结果来决定你的幸福感
are you going to let the impact of that define your happiness or not?
我觉得关键就在这儿
And I think that that's the thing.
当那些结果可能迟迟不出现时
When the impacts maybe are not coming,
你就得去调整成这样一种状态
you have to then adapt to,
好，我到底想把什么当作自己的幸福来源
okay, what do I want my happiness to be?
有一位冥想老师说过
And one of the meditation teachers said,
人生真正的自由，是在得不到自己想要的东西时，依然学会心满意足
the true freedom in life is learning how to be content when you don't get what you want.
这并不是说当你得不到想要的东西时就什么都不该做
And it's not to say you shouldn't do something when you don't get what you want.
但我觉得这里面最重要的一点是
But I think that that takeaway of just,
你能不能在不依赖得到某样东西的前提下，依然感到满足
can you be content and not have your happiness rely on getting something?
我觉得这很有挑战
I think it's a challenge.
我自己也做得不完美
I'm not perfect at it,
但这大概是整件事里我最大的收获之一
but I think it's probably one of the biggest takeaways from that whole thing.
太棒了 如果大家想看这篇文章 我们会把链接放在说明里
Incredible. And we'll link to the post if folks want to read this.
在进入非常精彩的快问快答之前
Before we get to a very exciting lightning round,
你还有什么想分享的吗 还是我们直接开始
is there anything else you wanted to share or should we just jump right in?
我觉得我们可以直接开始
I think we can jump into it.
我们已经聊了很多内容了
We covered a lot of ground.
好 那我们开始
Okay, here we go.
我这儿有五个问题要问你
I've got five questions for you.
第一个问题 你最常推荐给别人的两三本书是什么
First question, what are two or three books you recommend most to other people?
大概会和我刚才讲的很多内容有关
Probably ties to a lot of what I just talked about.
我经常在思考冥想和自己的情绪状态
I think a lot about meditation and my emotional state.
这就是我在工作之外花最多时间去思考 阅读 研究 和实践的东西
That's what I spend most of my time thinking and reading and researching and working on outside of work.
所以我推荐的书也和这些非常相关
So my recommendation is very related to that.
第一本是一本叫《Joy of Living》的书 作者是一位佛教僧人
The first is a book called Joy of Living by a Buddhist monk.
His name is Yonggi Mingyur Rinpoche.
他叫Yongey Mingyur Rinpoche
它主要讲的是 你如何开始用一种不同的方式来看待自己的人生体验
It's just really about how you can start to think about your life experience in a
以及有哪些具体方法可以帮助你改变自己看待事物的思维方式
different way and have tactics of what to do to kind of change just how you think about things.
这本书是我经常推荐给别人的
This is one where I've recommended it to people.
不是那种随口一提的推荐 很多人看了之后都非常喜欢
It's not like, yeah, it recommends a lot of people and they've really, really enjoyed it.
I think another one is Awareness by Anthony DeMello,
另一本文字是Anthony DeMello写的《Awareness》
主题有点类似
which is a kind of similar thing,
但切入角度不太一样
but from a different angle.
这两本是我一直在推荐给大家的书
Those two I consistently recommend to people.
第三本在很多方面和产品更相关 是Annie Duke写的《Thinking in Bets》
And then the third one is more relevant to product in many ways is Thinking in Bets by Annie Duke.
我觉得 当有人说
I think just being able to break down a situation when someone's like,
我也不知道 反正应该能按时完成 吧
I don't know, it'll get done in time.
这时候你就可以说 好 那你能不能给个数字
Okay, like, can you put a number to that?
比如说 你觉得有多少百分比的可能性能按时完成
Like, what percentage likelihood is it?
这种思维方式在做产品时 在具体操作层面上非常有帮助
Those types of things I think are just so tactically helpful in product.
最近最喜欢的电影或电视剧是什么
Favorite recent movie or TV show?
I think movie is probably Marty Supreme.
电影的话大概是《Marty Supreme》
这是我最近为数不多看过的电影之一
It's one of the only ones I watched recently.
我觉得特别好
I thought it was great.
我觉得这电影简直疯了 真的非常疯狂
I thought it was just insane, absolutely insane movie.
荒诞到不行 但我超喜欢
It was ridiculous, but I loved it.
电视剧的话 我已经有一阵子没看电视了
TV show, I have not watched TV in a while.
要算的话 可能最近看的就是奥运会
I think it's probably the Olympics would be the one if that counts.
有没有一个你特别喜欢的产品
Is there a product that you love just like,
不管是你最近发现的 还是你生活中一直在用的
I don't know, when you discovered recently or just when you have in your life that's like,
让你觉得 哇 这也太酷了
oh, this is very cool.
你觉得大家可能会想知道一下
People might want to know about it.
有 这个还挺好笑的
Yeah, so this is a funny one.
我上周在日本住酒店时，睡在那家酒店里，我真的非常喜欢自己用的那个枕头
I was in Japan last week and I was sleeping in this hotel and I actually really loved the pillow that I had in this hotel.
这事儿特别随机
It was very random.
我有时候会脖子和上斜方肌疼 对自己的
At times I had like neck and upper trap pain and sometimes I've been frustrated with my
枕头也挺不满意 因为我有时候仰睡
pillow because I sometimes sleep facing up,
有时候侧睡 枕头高度总是不太合适
sometimes sideways and like the height's not quite right.
然后我就觉得 这个枕头也太好了
And I was like, this pillow is just great.
基本上这个枕头里面是装满了小颗粒
And basically this pillow is like it kind of it's full of beads.
所以你在睡觉的时候可以很自然地调整枕头的高度
And so you can like naturally shift the height of the pillow while you're sleeping,
甚至是无意识地 不用刻意去想
like even like unconsciously without thinking.
然后我就看了一下标签
And and so I looked at the tag.
心想 这到底是什么牌子
I was like, what is this?
我就在日本亚马逊上下单 买了一个 然后坐飞机带回来了
I ordered it to Amazon Japan and I brought it back with me on the plane.
所以我这儿有它的名字
And so I have the name here.
It's called the Maruhachi Shinsui Maruhachi Pro Pillow.
它叫 Maruhachi Shinsui Maruhachi Pro Pillow
你只能在日本买到它
And you can only get it in Japan,
不过他们可以寄到美国
but they ship to the US.
没有任何商业关系 但我觉得在过去这一周 它简直改变了我的生活
No affiliation. And I think that has changed my life in like the last week.
这个推荐太棒了
That is an awesome pick.
你在工作或生活中 有没有经常会想起的座右铭
Do you have a favorite life motto that you often come back to in work or in life?
Main one I'd say is just, she'll be right.
我最常说的一句大概是 “she'll be right”
这是澳洲人特别常说的一句话
This is a very common Aussie saying.
字面意思就是 “一切都会好的”
It's like, she will be right.
“She'll be right” 是澳洲人在面对困难或棘手情况时常说的一句话
She'll be right. It's a common Aussie saying when we're faced with like a tough or difficult situation.
你有点是在淡化事情的严重性 好像在说 没事儿 一切都会好的
You're kind of like dismissing the severity of it in a way by saying like, it'll be fine.
我觉得这是一个特别好的比喻
And I think that that's just like such a good metaphor.
在很多很多情况下 这都是一个特别好用的心态技巧
It's such a good like tactic in many, many cases.
另外一句是
And then I think the other one is just like,
人生有时候 你就是得豁出去干一把
sometimes in life, you just have to go for it.
这是一个叫Eros Resmini的人常说的话
And that is something that this guy Eros Resmini,
他是Discord的首席营销官
who is the CMO of Discord,
在我做创业者 / 创始人的时候 他是我非常亲近的顾问
he was a very close advisor to me as a founder.
他经常在这方面鼓励我
He would push me on this.
他经常对我说的就是
And that was something that he would often say is just like,
别想太多 就去干
just go for it.
我觉得这句话
And I think that that's,
非常有帮助 因为你完全可以一直坐在那里想
it's a very helpful thing of you can sit there thinking,
我该不该做 该不该试
should I do this, should I not?
但人生有时候
And sometimes in life,
你就是得上 就是得去做
you just have to go for it.
我特别喜欢这两句搭在一起
I love the combo of those two.
有时候就是大胆去做 然后一切都会好的
Just sometimes just go for it and she'll be right.
太棒了 好 最后一个问题
So good. Okay, final question.
好的 那我很好奇
Okay, so I'm curious,
你以前很迷武术
you used to be into martial arts.
结果不是很理想
That didn't go great.
你现在有没有特别喜欢上的新爱好
Do you have a new hobby that you find yourself loving?
你会专门为兴趣爱好腾出时间吗
Do you make time for hobbies?
我觉得吧 我在兴趣爱好上真的时间挺紧张的
I think I'm just like quite tight on time for hobbies, I would say.
基本上我的时间就是
I think it's largely just like,
工作 然后让身体还能正常运转
work and have my body function.
然后你也知道
And then like, you know,
照顾好身边最重要的那些关系
take care of the most important relationships around me.
要说唯一算得上爱好的
I think maybe the one hobby I'd say is just,
就是我特别喜欢体育
I'm really into sports.
而且最近更迷体育 尤其是橄榄球
And I've gotten more into sports and football in particular.
是看 是看 绝对不是自己上场打
Watching. Watching. Certainly not playing.
我妻子来自密歇根
My wife's from Michigan,
她带我去“大房子”看了一场球
and she took me to a game at the big house.
那次经历简直改变了我的人生
And it just changed my life.
从那以后我就觉得
From then on, I was like,
我是金刚狼队的球迷了
I'm a Wolverines fan.
又是铁杆金刚狼球迷 也是铁杆49人球迷
And big Wolverines fan, big 49ers fan.
我就是太爱橄榄球了
I just love football.
所以这大概是我能想到的唯一一个爱好
So that's probably the one that comes to mind.
Amol 这次对话在很多层面上都太精彩了
Amol, this was incredible on so many levels.
非常感谢你抽时间来参加
I am so thankful that you made time for this,
尤其是考虑到你现在事情这么多
considering how much you got going on.
大家在网上可以去哪儿找到你
Where can folks find you online?
比如说他们想来应聘
Say they want to apply for a job,
也许是加入你的团队
maybe on your team?
他们该去哪儿找相关信息
Where can they find that?
听众们又能怎样对你有所帮助
And how can listeners be useful to you?
你们可以在我的 LinkedIn 上找到我
You can find me on my LinkedIn.
就叫 Amol Avasare 很无聊的那种用户名
It's just Amol Avasare. I'm boring.
就这样 你可以上网到我们的招聘页面投简历 上面会陆续发布增长工程
That's it. You can look online to apply on our jobs page as it rolls across growth engineering,
增长产品 增长设计等岗位
growth product, growth design.
我们正在为增长团队寻找优秀的人才
We are looking for great people on the growth team.
所以欢迎大家来加入我们
So please come and join us.
我觉得对我来说最有帮助的就两件事
And I think being helpful to me is just two things.
试用我们的产品 然后给我们反馈
Trying our products, giving us feedback,
尤其是尖锐的反馈 告诉我们哪里还能做得更好
giving us harsh feedback in particular on what can be better.
另外也请把优秀的人才介绍给我们
And then please send great people our way.
我们在寻找最顶尖的人加入团队
We are looking for the best of the best to join the team.
也非常期待你介绍任何你认识的 可能适合我们岗位的人来联系
And we would love to hear from anyone you know as well who could be a fit for one of our roles.
对很多人来说这都是梦寐以求的工作
Dream job for so many people.
Amol 非常感谢你来做客
Amol, thank you so much for being here.
谢谢你 Lenny 大家再见
Thanks, Lenny. Bye, everyone.
非常感谢你的收听
Thank you so much for listening.
如果你觉得这期内容有价值
If you found this valuable,
你可以在 Apple Podcasts、Spotify 或你常用的播客应用中订阅本节目
you can subscribe to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite podcast app.
也欢迎给我们评分或留下评论
Also, please consider giving us a rating or leaving a review,
这会真正帮助更多听众发现这个播客
as that really helps other listeners find the podcast.
你可以在 lennypodcast.com 找到所有往期节目 或了解更多关于本节目的信息
You can find all past episodes or learn more about the show at lennypodcast.com.
我们下期节目再见
See you in the next episode!